Krish NAik: Yeah, hello everyone, am I audible? Please let me know in the charts, guys.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: All right, I think Phoebe will have joined today.
Krish NAik: Really, any update, alright, just wait, let me just, first of all.
Krish NAik: Start hunting.
Krish NAik: First, wait, let me open the chat.
Krish NAik: Oh, no, I'm not, well, so… Today also, like, it, I'll be taking few inputs for the Project 4 for that, actually, a giant otherwise.
Krish NAik: wouldn't have joined, okay? So, just with desktop, too. Because for a multimodal drag, the main thing is, like.
Krish NAik: you guys need to get GPUs, and for GPUs, like, free GPUs aren't actually helping. I have done a lot of testing in Collab, but really, Google Collab is not holding it so much well.
Krish NAik: So I'm planning to move to a proper GPU-based, infrastructure. And for that, probably, like.
Krish NAik: So that's the thing I'll be discussing today. Okay, so, generally the stack, and for complex documents, exactly how to build a stack. Okay, so a few things with respect to multimodal rack that I will start. With respect to the practicals, I will discuss the practicals later on. Okay, first of all, the main idea is to build a stack.
Krish NAik: Okay, for everyone.
Krish NAik: Okay, because the stack with respect to text is totally different, and the stack for
Krish NAik: Images, audio, okay, that is totally different.
Krish NAik: Now, the main problem is any type of model, if you are working with, like, for embeddings, you have a separate, vision embedding models. If you know in the last week, like, Gemma got launched. Anybody saw it in LinkedIn or somewhere in the post?
Krish NAik: the new embedding GEMA model.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, that is there, okay. A lot of others are there. Now, the idea is to decide the stack, actually, okay? So today, we'll be working on that, because that will be your project folder, the stack that you decide.
Krish NAik: And to work on that stack, like, the bare minimum. So, one is the API-based approach that I'll be talking about. Okay, now I have taken a simple example of complex documents like this. Now, you can understand that, normal
Krish NAik: PDF parsers won't work. So here, actually, we have to work with VLNs.
Krish NAik: Okay, and probably, otherwise, I have to take an OCR-based approach. It means that probably I'll be using Nestral OCR, because again, if I select something open source, deep-seq OCR, and if I try to run it in my machine, then again, I need a GPU. At every point of time, this will be a challenge.
Krish NAik: So, I am planning to switch to Lightning, okay, because I feel that without Lightning, the main problem with Google Collab, if I'm working with any of the stuff, okay, so, like, simple…
Krish NAik: I can say simple things can be executed.
Krish NAik: But, that entire thing, for example, I was planning to work with Minery, okay, because minor use actually used in production.
Krish NAik: It means that you should always have a fallback condition. If this doesn't work, then I have to switch to this one.
Krish NAik: And if… and minor you, nobody will provide you the direct API. There is an API, but again, that's a Chinese website. It becomes very hard, actually, and the website is very, very slow. Okay, so I was planning to host it
Krish NAik: Then only, because two things, like Dockling, table transformers, and miner.
Krish NAik: Okay, for enterprise documents, I can say that, Docklink is really good. Again, but we have Llama Pass also, if you remember, we have discussed Llama Pass.
Krish NAik: Now, for this, the requirement of RAM is really, really high, so I'll be talking about that tech stack right now, okay? One is the API-based approach, if we go ahead with it.
Krish NAik: API-based approach means everything API. It means that we won't be using anything. But again, for those APIs, also, you have to pay. So, for example, like, how many of you know about Replicate? Anybody knows about Replicate? Or Hugging Face, Inference?
Krish NAik: Anybody hugging Face and Currents?
Krish NAik: Because if I try to totally avoid, then also, now, these are inference providers
Krish NAik: like, any type of inference, if I'm trying to do. Then again, what I have to do, I have to actually select the model, I have to select an infrastructure, and then I have to host that model. For that, also, I need to pay.
Krish NAik: It means that there are no free things that actually I can include in this stuff, okay? So, I've prepared a document, and I'll be doing step-by-step, actually, the stack that we'll be discussing. So, first of all, let me just open my notes and tell you the generic things
Krish NAik: Like, what are the core components? And inside those components, what are the things that you can… so you guys can let me know. I'll be taking your inputs, because for project 4, exactly, based on your inputs, I will present the project.
Krish NAik: Okay, so step by step, let's start with the first of all.
Krish NAik: Lang extracted, people are saying lang… lettuce Lang extract is doing it all. Not all, I can say. Okay, so just wait. Okay, MS and others, just wait. Let me start sharing my notes.
Krish NAik: Documents, advance, iPad wire, please.
Krish NAik: Well, I hope everybody can see my screen.
Krish NAik: Now, to build any type of multimodal rack pipeline, Okay, so…
Krish NAik: You know, what happened to my… Apple pencil, just to be…
Krish NAik: Right, it's not working. Fine, let's leave it, and let me go back to the charts. The pencil is not charged. Give it 5 minutes.
Krish NAik: Hmm… alright.
Krish NAik: Let's switch to, Z, okay? Now, these are the system requirements that I'll be talking about. Before that, let's talk about the stack. So,
Krish NAik: Whenever I am building any multimodal rack system. So, first of all, you need a good quality dock pass.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: This is the first step. Once you have the document parser, now, with that parser, what are… you have the options to do? Work with OCR. And why you need OCR? What is the purpose of using OCR? Because the document extractor can work with text, you know that already. Okay, but you also have images.
Krish NAik: Okay, now.
Krish NAik: I'm taking these images. Now, these images can be a lot of things. I'm taking all the images, everything, like, let's take here, normal images, then comes your diagrams.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes your charts.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes your tables, everything.
Krish NAik: All those things. Okay, for those things, I need a good quality OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this OCR selection is also important. So, I'll be telling you the stack in OCRs, what are the best options right now in 2026,
Krish NAik: So, any new OCR you guys know about, which got launched recently, Anybody?
Krish NAik: Today, we are talking about the multimodal stack Weber is joining. Okay, and Nemotron, yes, correct. Nemotron stack is also really good, we can work on that, but first of all, I'll be working pretty much on an open-source stack, and then I will be discussing about it.
Krish NAik: Okay, Nemotron also we can actually use, because, NVIDIA gives you free credits, okay? In their, build, they have a developer platform. From there, you can get close to 5,000 credits, and you can select NVIDIA Nemotron, so that is good.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the part where we need to take our first decision. Okay, like, what are the components? So, for example, if I pick something like Mestral OCR, okay, or Azure Doc Intelligence, this also I can take
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, here comes your minor.
Krish NAik: Okay. So, all this, stack, and really, the list is really, really long. Okay, I cannot cover all, so we have to freeze, like, exactly what will be.
Krish NAik: There. So, in the other document, I have kept it. Now, once you have solved the problem of OCR, okay? So, after OCR,
Krish NAik: The main thing will be image emittance.
Krish NAik: Okay, for this also, the model that we'll be working with, it will be a bigger one, so not every embeddings
Krish NAik: So, I think you guys already know about NUMIC.
Krish NAik: Then, you have Jenna, then you have Gemini, basically GemmaBase, the new one which got launched last week. That is also good. So, from there, we'll be picking up anyone. So, for example, if I go ahead with Voaj Multimodal.
Krish NAik: Okay, multi-modal, this one. Okay, this is really good, so I'm talking about… but again, this is also paid. I hope everybody knows about that. And the open source alternative to this?
Krish NAik: Yes, anybody who has explored a little bit?
Krish NAik: The other is Polquin 2.5.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is from the Quinn family, and it requires close to, like.
Krish NAik: 8GB of VRAM. Nothing on CPU, everything is based on VRAM, okay? So here, GINA is also there, so GINA is the V4 version that got launched, that is also… So, from here, we'll be picking one, okay? Now, once we have solved the problem of image embeddings, then we have that,
Krish NAik: Once we have this table information, for example, with respect to charts, tables, anything, diagrams, okay, now we need something like a proper, table extractor.
Krish NAik: So that any information that comes within the tables, that should be properly, extracted. So for that, like, the easiest one is Docklink provides table, formulas, okay? Or the other option that I can go ahead with, like, you can get this information directly to GPT-4. Let's take.
Krish NAik: Because for this, really, you don't need to select anything. Okay. Now, this is the other option. You can work with any multimodal.
Krish NAik: LLX. MLLM, that's why I will say MLLM is one of the options. So, through an API-based call, we can solve this problem. So, this is not really a big problem.
Krish NAik: Now the question comes about hybrid retrieval.
Krish NAik: This is where a lot of things will come.
Krish NAik: So, one is sparse, okay? Then comes your tense.
Krish NAik: Okay, now the question comes about, here will be… I'm planning to get, like,
Krish NAik: One can be your, pool pali.
Krish NAik: Okay, Pulpali is an older one. We have the newer versions and the better versions of Pulpali.
Krish NAik: But, because through this only, you will be doing the extraction. So, for example, I do have a notebook that I'll be discussing before working on the project. So, like, directly you can make your image-based retrievals through CoalPali, and it's really good, I can say. But again, like, you need VRAM. Without a VRAM, it doesn't work.
Krish NAik: So, here also, if I show you… so, roughly, the model size that you can get it here. So, can you see here, downloaded 8GB?
Krish NAik: So whenever, like, 8GB, will be sitting on your VRAM, whenever you will be. So this is actually the cool value implementation, just the demo part, which I have kept it.
Krish NAik: In image embedding, how to store it? Okay, that is a… that is easier, actually. Like, in a single connection… in a single collection only, we can save it. It can be quadrant, it can be millers. I'm not worried about saving image embeddings, but…
Krish NAik: Like, in a single collection, I think you guys know that we can create multiple indexes, one index for text, one index for images, and that way we can see better, right?
Krish NAik: Splate, yes, we can work with split. See, anything that I have discussed till now, in text, everything you can add in. Okay, so, like, you can add Splate also. I have no issues, as we have discussed Splate.
Krish NAik: Now, here you can add Colbert… okay, so split or culvert is also fine. So, that part also you can add.
Krish NAik: Anybody remember Schoolbert? Your multi-vector approach?
Krish NAik: that part also that you can add. So, a lot of things. And here, finally, an RRF fusion that I am planning for your hybrid, too.
Krish NAik: Okay, and here, some type of millivers, quadrant, anything will work. The free things, like 2GB, I know the limits are there. We'll be picking up cloud. Local, I won't be using. Now, and finally comes your last one, which is the,
Krish NAik: VLLMs here. Now, this is the part where the RAG will do the reasoning. It means that from here, it will get the context. Okay, now this is the part where you will be fetching out the context. Now, from the context part.
Krish NAik: Once you have that, you know that, okay, so probably, like, let's take 5 chunks, 10 chunks, 15 chunks at core, then the final process. Now, this is also the easy part, nothing you have to do. Let's stick with GPT-4.
Krish NAik: as we have worked with GPT-40 a lot.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I think this is the month it will get duplicated also by 31st March, so we can use any GPT-5 version, or 5.12 in that way we can sell it. Or something from NVIDIA also, which got recently launched, like the Nemotron Super and others.
Krish NAik: Okay. So, first of all, like, the main thing is this part, that we need to really figure it out. Okay, so that's why
Krish NAik: I picked up a stack, based on this particular options that now I'll be deciding. Now, the simplest way, I'll be showing you how much VRAM you want.
Krish NAik: Now, the question comes, everybody, please let me know. Now, this is the first question that I am asking to you in today's class.
Krish NAik: Should we go ahead with… entirely with an API-based approach? It means that nothing in your local.
Krish NAik: But you have to do the payment to get the APIs. You have to use any platform, like, Replicate, okay, or your, Hugging Face, inference providers. So should we get only API-based stuff? It means that for everything, you'll be paying through the APIs.
Krish NAik: Okay, or the local part system, because based on your chats, okay, just wait, let me open the chats. Guys, don't type now. Let me open so that everybody can get a, clear prospect. Panelist, attenders, okay, yes, I've changed the chat settings, okay? So, everybody, please type now, so that others can also see. How much is the payment, roughly?
Krish NAik: $20 you can take.
Krish NAik: Till the time in the project. Say, don't say both. Both becomes a problem, so why will pay for both of the things you have to understand? Whoever is telling both.
Krish NAik: you will pay for API also, you will pay for infrastructure. Does it make any sense? I feel that, if you know the local part, later on, easily you can switch to API.
Krish NAik: So, the local part, I feel that it's much. Now, whenever you are working with local stuff, okay, so, in my main document, that's why I've taken, multiple profiles of working on the project. First is the free tire, which is the API-based. So, here, I will be actually paying for everything.
Krish NAik: Now, just think about minary. I have to host this minary on some platform. Okay, docklink, this is the local. Can you see your local local when it's written? It means that local CPU docklink will work. Then, again, OCR, I have to, for example, I have taken a simple example of Nemame here.
Krish NAik: which is the NVIDIA. This is, again, API, image embedding, again, API. If I'm selecting, then table extraction, table format, this dock link can do. Now, this is a completely. So,
Krish NAik: And here, T416 can do the job, because it's nothing… everything, you are actually pushing it to the API. But nothing will be cleaned, I can say. It means that high-level abstraction.
Krish NAik: For any type of approaches that you are doing. Okay, so this is the profile one, which is the API-based approach. Now, as people are telling in the chat, majorly.
Krish NAik: Api, will be better as we change the API and implementation quickly. No, you have to understand, when I say API, it's not like that. API is also simple. So, for example, let's take replicate.
Krish NAik: Now, whenever you are working here, okay, so let's me go to the dashboard section.
Krish NAik: anyone. Okay, so I think,
Krish NAik: I set up the payment already, just wait.
Krish NAik: Hmm?
Krish NAik: Add credits, okay, alright. Now, okay, whenever you are, actually working with any models.
Krish NAik: Okay, can you see here, no models found? So, you have to actually host the model, and then you have to pay the model. It means that the hosting and everything will be taken care by Replicate or Hugging Face. So, any one platform, you guys can use it. It means that you won't be manually doing it, so these guys will be taking care of that.
Krish NAik: But again, like, nothing from your side if something is down, so… Now, this is really costly, don't think about this as cheap. So here, also, you'll be spending close to…
Krish NAik: $10 to $20. Okay, so that's why. When you select a model, like, you have to create a model, okay, who can see the model, what will be the name, push a custom model, can you see here? So from here, like, what will be the requirement? You have to select on which GPU, because if I'm going ahead with Minor U and others, so you have to actually host this.
Krish NAik: Now, I feel that, local gives you much more power rather than taking it. Okay, how much RAM required? RAM not. We need VRAM. And the minimum VRAM, for our local, I feel that you need, 30GB of VRAM.
Krish NAik: Okay, minimi mom, I am telling.
Krish NAik: At least, for the demos, I can show you to a certain limit where at least under 24 GB, most of the things will be done. But again, for our project, not possible. If we are working with a good pipeline, it means that if docklink doesn't work, then the fallback will, be going back to minoring.
Krish NAik: So that's why, like, these GPUs, everything. So, for example, if I select, L40S, like, I feel that in this particular course, we do need to work with H100s or A100s. Actually, these are for enterprises. Okay, for our local tutorial, I feel that L40S is good.
Krish NAik: It gives you, like, a good amount of RAM, something like, L40, that will be the max limit I'm planning for this course. Okay, now take a look at the pricing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, these are a few available models which are already hosted, and you can see, per second, 0.25.
Krish NAik: Can you see per second?
Krish NAik: guide.
Krish NAik: 0.1 per thousand output tokens. Like, this, this is Deep Sea Carbon, so I'm showing you a rough estimated pricing.
Krish NAik: In our case, majorly, like, this is video stuff, we won't be working with video, so Majorly, we'll be working. I think, it can be, like, anthropic models or something like,
Krish NAik: This one. Okay, Flux Dev…
Krish NAik: Okay, now these are some boosted image-based models that I'm telling. So, this is pricey. Actually, let's take an example. I have passed a PDF document.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think something like this. Now, from this PDF, let's take, 50 images are extracted. Okay, now, for those 50 images, you can take a rough estimated price when you look into this one. 0.04 into 50. Now, that is only for one single demo, not for your project.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's where the setup is a little bit, whether you want to go ahead with API, so that's why I've created this. Now, inference profile. This is the profile one where you can actually work everything, like, NVIDIA, they give you credits, so from NVIDIA also, we can pick a few of the things.
Krish NAik: But, again, the credits will be exhausted, so we have to do very limited temp for that.
Krish NAik: Now, the next option, now, this is the part where I feel that this is safe around. The sweet spot that I've selected, okay, 4R, which I feel that it's good. Now, why here? I feel that we can actually work around, like, 24GB of VRAM to 30GB.
Krish NAik: Because, there are a few things. So, for example, like, minor U. Only the extraction suit. Like, minor U has a lot of other things in its component, but if I only use the extraction suit, that becomes close to 4GB. Then comes your OCR.
Krish NAik: Padalusia. Again, completely open source, and you can actually use it. You can do the complete setup, 223GB. So, a rough estimate, it's like, this is…
Krish NAik: Cut to cut, you have to understand, like, in my, bucket, out of, so, like, if they are taking 24 GB, I have to take extra 6 GB always.
Krish NAik: as a buffer, okay? So, like, 20 to 30% of the GPU, so that if some process comes into the picture, it doesn't… the entire pipeline doesn't break. So, for that, I can limit my GPU
Krish NAik: to 80% of usage only, and 20% for 10 per minimum. Okay, now this is the recommended stack that I feel. But again, you can see, this is really tight.
Krish NAik: Okay. And, so I feel that around 30GB will be somewhere, around a good spot.
Krish NAik: And I'll be working a lot with the Docker, because I feel that a lot of things where Docker images are directly available.
Krish NAik: Okay, you really don't need the setup, you just need the infra. Then you can directly run the Docker image in that particular GPU, and the rest of the things will be up. So, like, Docker is the easier approach, or sometimes you really need to work on the code.
Krish NAik: Now, let me just show you, because here I have not taken anything from
Krish NAik: Name from NVIDIA? Okay, fine. Name from NVIDIA I can actually pick up.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, This, okay, now the full VRAM budget, okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, now these are the configurations that I have pulled, okay.
Krish NAik: Actually, like, minority will take more RAM. This is 4GB, which is approximate, but I know… because in my practical, I have seen it has gone, like, 7GB, 8GB also.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now, this is the entire, if you look into MinorU, Docklink plus Devil Farmers, Paddle OCR,
Krish NAik: Lama Nematron, Embed, Lama Nemotron, so a lot of things from, like, the NVIDIA family that we can pick up and we can use it. Because in this course, till now, we have not really explored the NVIDIA family, and let me just tell you the…
Krish NAik: How many of you know about blueprints from NVIDIA? Anybody who has explored in their enterprise or production? Because that's only for production, nobody teaches it for learning or for fun.
Krish NAik: Anybody has used?
Krish NAik: Alright. NVIDIA AI Blueprint, Rabbit.
Krish NAik: I think somewhere I will get that particular.
Krish NAik: This is the blueprint for Radjust.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is completely an NVIDIA stack I'm talking about. Now, this is really, really good, but it takes a huge amount of RAM. Okay, it means that for everything, NVIDIA has everything you have to understand, every, component. But to execute this stuff, you need at least
Krish NAik: 80GB of VRAM to do the execution. So, I'm not planning to use entirely the entire stack from NVIDIA, but to pick a few of the components.
Krish NAik: From NVIDIA. Okay, so this is really great if you want to look into architectures and other stuff. It gives you a really good idea from architects, okay, if you are actually using the NVIDIA stuff. This is a really good one. So you can really check it out for your multimodal setup. Okay, I'll be sharing this link so that later on you can
Krish NAik: You guys can actually explore this. So my implementation will be highly based on this one.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: inspired from this particular blueprint from NVIDIA. Later on, we can work on a project, but let's keep the stuff minimal so that everybody here can do it. And, one benefit from NVIDIA is you can use their Enterprise Edition free for 90 days. Unlimited access for 90 days.
Krish NAik: Everyone, I'm telling you about that. That is the… it means that you won't be charged a single penny for 90 days, and later on, you can cancel the subscription.
Krish NAik: That is the added benefit with NVIDIA. In the free trial, I think they give you limited credits, close to 5,000.
Krish NAik: But, the Enterprise, the trial version of the Enterprise, it's, like, unlimited for 90 days.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now, mmm.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, Deepak, the final summarization will come after 1 hour, so don't think about, right now, I can summarize everything. So I'm telling you everything step-by-step, like, what are the things that we will be talking about?
Krish NAik: All right, now let's get back here.
Krish NAik: No, this is…
Krish NAik: the actual production pipeline that I was talking about, which I will be preferring, okay, and I will be using, which is Lightning. I think, multiple times I have told in this course also that Lightning is really good.
Krish NAik: Because directly, I can get the subs for people working with AWS GCP from their marketplace, also, you can actually get Lightning. And I feel that this will be one of the cheapest options. Like, I feel $20 that you'll be spending
Krish NAik: all of your practicals that also that you can do, okay, as well as, like, your project also that you can do. The entire setup for the project, because this is the major stat where you need at least 48GB. This is the bare minimum that I am telling that we'll be working.
Krish NAik: Because 24GB, I can show you a few demos, but again, not the full potential of all VLMs I cannot show. So it will be, like, that, somewhere stuck.
Krish NAik: Because, I feel that from interview perspective, multimodal rack systems are much more important as compared to only text-based systems. Because in real world.
Krish NAik: you always… you will be working with PDFs, PPTs, XLS, okay, and images will always be there, as well as work, okay? Now, what is Lightning? Lightning is, like, here you get directly VSport support, so for example.
Krish NAik: And it's easy, actually, like, you don't really need to take care. Anybody have explored Lightning?
Krish NAik: Okay, then probably I can show you from my, office line, just wait.
Krish NAik: This is the lightning I just did.
Krish NAik: It's one click, so for developers, I feel that it is much better. Let me just go to my…
Krish NAik: Okay, and here, every month, if you are using your office mail, you can get close to 15 credits, okay? So I know that demos will be done, but for your project, so 15 credits you will get it. You guys can sign up, and you can test it out. And now, what is the best thing? So, here, if I select…
Krish NAik: dedicated core of GPU. Okay, so let me just increase that.
Krish NAik: Why I will prefer this, I need an,
Krish NAik: 4 CPUs, sorry, I will be working with GPUs, so at least L40S, if I am telling. Okay, so you can see, so this is the amount of credits that will be exhausted per hour.
Krish NAik: 2.89, so at least for one GPU. And later on, I can actually switch to multi-GPUs also.
Krish NAik: So, let me just confirm and let me launch for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, you guys can get a rough idea. So, this is directly VS Code. It means that the code that I'll be sharing
Krish NAik: you can directly do a Git clone here, and you can start your work. Pretty much like EWS SageMaker, I think you guys have worked with SageMaker and other stuff.
Krish NAik: Somewhere. In Azure, also, the same thing happens. In Google Vertex, also, you have a very similar configuration. I think you guys know about SageMaker. Somewhere in machine learning journey, you might have worked with SageMaker Studio. Okay. Now, what is the added benefit that I feel that
Krish NAik: Here, actually, I can switch instantly in one click.
Krish NAik: from, my GPU to GPU.
Krish NAik: Which is not possible in any other plants.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that just think about if I'm doing only my development task. If I am writing code, and if I do… do you think that I need the GPU?
Krish NAik: Yes or no. If I'm just writing code.
Krish NAik: Do I need the GPU? No.
Krish NAik: I need the GPU only for execution, and this actually gives you that. Switch to CPU. It means that initially, okay, let's launch something with its GPU, and later on, I can actually switch to the GPU. So, they have a separate environment, so that's why I prefer, like, much more lightning. It's much cheaper in that way, because majorly, most of my development work, I know that CPU. Fine, like, I will, at least I can test out
Krish NAik: that majorly, I will get an OOM error, out-of-memory error. Put your CPU to GPU in one click.
Krish NAik: Now, this feature is not there, neither in SageMaker, neither in any cloud platform. So that's why if you take a proper AWS instance in SageMaker, it will continuously charge you.
Krish NAik: And for your project, I hope everybody understands that
Krish NAik: Will we at least be executing it for continuously
Krish NAik: at least I can say, let's take 4 classes, so, like, 15 to 16 hours.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the charge that will come, it will be very high. So, this is an added, benefit. So, even if you launch a CPU, you can actually switch, easily to some other, GPU also. So in one click, a lot of things that can be changed here. So, this is the added benefit. So, I'm planning, actually, to use this one.
Krish NAik: And, right now, once everything is there, it's simply, like, rest of the things, like a normal VS Code.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is not provided for free in Google Collab also.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, if you, look here.
Krish NAik: So, how much VRAM that I have? In free, they are giving you. They are not pricing. So, this is not an account that I have paid till now. Later on, like, once I do the final setup, so I'm thinking that this is good. And the pricing also, like, in collab, you have $10, I feel that
Krish NAik: Here you have the entire system with you. It means that you can run Docker. You can run everything here.
Krish NAik: Whereas in Collab, working with Docker is not possible only.
Krish NAik: I hope you get it, like, why I'm telling this and why. So, you have to always evaluate, like, which platform. Now, this is actually providing me an entire thing, so I feel that this is much safer to work with, and majorly all of our practicals will be done.
Krish NAik: Okay, now the question comes, like, for me, the pricing shows, like, I know the pro version is $50, but for you, is it showing $20? Please have it checked. I'm sharing this URL, try to open this and let me know that for you. Is it showing $50 or, $20?
Krish NAik: Because, the main problem is.
Krish NAik: If I go with the monthly plan, it'll be showing $50. No, no, see, you don't go click on annual. Annual means $20.
Krish NAik: Okay, annual, I'm not talking about.
Krish NAik: look for monthly, because I don't want you guys. Later on, you can actually… if you're doing a lot of R&D stuff, then only it's good, I had to pay for such a long time, up to $40 commitment. But, $50, this says…
Krish NAik: the one that I feel that it will do. But again, I feel that this is, pretty much costly as compared to others. And they have an academic pricing also, but I know that every
Krish NAik: student cannot work with the academic pricing, because I don't think, everybody will have .adu accounts. In that case, it becomes much cheaper. You can see 40 monthly credits. Now, I think if I go ahead with an ADU account.
Krish NAik: I think I have my… it's a global.
Krish NAik: I think academic pricing, okay, now here it can be enabled, actually. This is a .2 account. Okay, so this is, like,
Krish NAik: Much cheaper, $10, and you get 100 annual credits.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the academic pricing per month. For student, it's cheaper, but really, for initial testing, I feel this is. Now, really, we need to take the decision, like, what should we do? What are the things that we should not do?
Krish NAik: Okay, now, like, do we really want to stick to collab? Because collab is really the cheapest one, okay? But,
Krish NAik: Nothing with respect to Docker and other things, that is possible.
Krish NAik: Because this is for sure cheaper, you can say $11.79.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, this is, I think, 11.79.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's why, like, I know, affording $50 Hmm.
Krish NAik: the cost of these courses, I think?
Krish NAik: Close to that.
Krish NAik: Annual credit means for 365 days. Today you have purchased it, and you need to finish it within 365 days. And monthly credits are, like, within one month of that 30-day span, it will be exhausted.
Krish NAik: In Collab, yes, in Collab, the main limitation that I feel that I don't have pseudo-access. I hope everybody understands, whenever I'm working with a system.
Krish NAik: as a developer, I need at least not pseudo-access, at least user-level access.
Krish NAik: which collab doesn't provide, that is, and even, like, a lot of Docker Demon, the main Docker service that also I cannot execute. So, like, really. And just think about projects I cannot execute only. For your project, at least I can show you a few limited demos.
Krish NAik: Okay, even I was planning, so, like,
Krish NAik: planning for the demos, neither of them are working in collab. So, for example, if I show you my Granite notebook, yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, as I was testing it out, because this I'll be teaching you in class, this is Granite Multimodal from Dockling, this is a one.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, like, 50 images, it got extracted, but later on, let me just show you, like, what is the size of the model. From here, always try to analyze the model that I'm downloading.
Krish NAik: 4444444. So, close to 4, how many times are there 8? Now, this is Dockling Granite version, this is completely open source, but 32 GB of VRAM is required.
Krish NAik: For this particular demo to be executed.
Krish NAik: I have taken a lighter version. They're also, like, it picked around close to 8GB. I was trying to do a… I was trying to use a lower data type, so I actually switched from 32 to float 16.
Krish NAik: Okay, but again, then, actually, it hampers the performance of the model. And later on, actually, like, in the original version, it was working, but later on, if I show you some of the images which have extract, I think.
Krish NAik: From here, just food.
Krish NAik: Because I'm giving you a rough thing so that you guys at least can get
Krish NAik: Okay, now these are text. Okay, text things, there is no problem with text, but if I show you with respect to images… Okay, now can you see from the document that I was actually showing? Okay, so it's actually extracting every image, whatever the image will be there.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody gets it, like, this is the same thing that even I am planning to do for…
Krish NAik: Best for production, leave for production. Production, I'm not talking. In production, you'll be using much better GPUs, for sure. That is the enterprise stuff, so I'm not worried about enterprise.
Krish NAik: I'm only worried about the main stack that I'll be, like, doing it in our projects. Interface, you'll be using H100, for sure, and probably not one. You can use two also, to make things much more faster.
Krish NAik: Because on CPU, the inference time is very, very high. Like, for one image, it will take 3 minutes.
Krish NAik: So if you have 50 images, it is not possible, also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so can you see, like, everything, that part with respect to graphs, images, everything that can be extracted through this? Like, if you want to ask any question with respect to charts. So this is just exactly the thing that I am planning to do. I even,
Krish NAik: if I try to lower the data type, simply the results are being hampered. So, the plan is, like, which way to go ahead?
Krish NAik: like, collab, collab, collab? Or, like, should we work with Lightning? Because, I don't know how many of you have Academy, if you have really academic, that A2 account.
Krish NAik: really, like, it will be cheaper for you, and really, like, the same $9 per monthly, but that's the thing, everybody doesn't have a… how many of you have Edu accounts? Please let me know, because that becomes a problem. I know everybody is not a student, but somewhere in your life, you got an EDU account in… yes?
Krish NAik: Because that's the main thing, I feel that. Okay, one thing we can do, I think everybody has an official email account, okay? Please try to sign up in Lightning and just check, are you getting the 15?
Krish NAik: Created that one. Okay, so just wait.
Krish NAik: Let me just switch up that one for now. Okay, are you guys getting that, 15, credits or not? Please check that part.
Krish NAik: Okay, please check from your site, at least. Click on lightning.ai, and click on sign up, and use your office email. Don't use personal Gmails and others. For personal Gmail, the verification takes a long time. If you get in personal Gmail, it's good, but I will suggest use some type of office emails.
Krish NAik: Okay, or at least any customized domain, if you have something like that. Customized domains works. They don't prefer at the rate gmails.
Krish NAik: Can you check run port? Run port is fine, but again, in Runport, I don't have, always, okay, run port and modals are, again, a much more choice, but again, those are for deployments of only certain services, not for that entire particular project.
Krish NAik: For Runport also, I have no issues, like, if you really want to work with RunPod, I can pay Runport also. In Runport also, $50. But, in RunPod, you have to understand that, you can get… so, let me show you RunPod.
Krish NAik: Okay, so GPU on cloud.
Krish NAik: But this entire infra setup of VSport and others, that it won't give you. Okay, so here you have on-demand GPUs, clusters, but that entire VSport setup, and if you want any extension like codecs, clock to be working in that environment, it becomes much harder. So, Vasha, I hope you get it.
Krish NAik: This is, like, RunPot is also my favorite, but when I know that my stack is fixed, I want to deploy an embedding model here. Okay, I want to deploy an VLLM here, then I will be actually going in. RunPot is also good. Okay, the other alternate of RunPod is, Moodle. Anybody else heard about Moodle?
Krish NAik: This is also the competitor, of, Runport.
Krish NAik: Because these companies come to us, actually, like, sometimes it can be sponsored videos and other stuff, so I know that, and actually, I've worked with RunPod, it's really, really good. But again,
Krish NAik: the development experience is not so much good. I need that development experience, because I need code, I know something, so it'll be wrong. And now the question comes, how to easily switch anything. So from here, actually, I can easily expose my port. 8080, just take a bout. I will get an HTTP link in one click.
Krish NAik: I hope you guys can understand the exact scenario.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Jatin Darbal is telling for free account. Jatindar, really test it out, and if you are sure, okay, everybody in this class can do it, okay, then let me know.
Krish NAik: Yes, it will be verified in 2 to 3 days, that's why. The verification is faster if you have office emails.
Krish NAik: any office, or any custom, like, at the rate, if you have your own domain also, that works. If you have a mailbox for that, then also.
Krish NAik: Amar is asking, like, you are paying $20 to customer? That is different. I am not talking about your coding stuff.
Krish NAik: Office email will be saved? Yes, yes, totally safe.
Krish NAik: This is actually my old office email only, that nobody… 15 credits? First of all, just check that are you guys getting the free credits or not? That is the first step.
Krish NAik: Okay, and, Suli and Bahamut.
Krish NAik: Let me just switch it.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, everybody is getting 15, so at least we can start with the practicals here, I feel, and then slowly, slowly, you can take the decision after one or two weeks that should you invest? If you are getting this 15, this is free. Anyone can get it.
Krish NAik: 15 credits, everybody please check. Because right now, I'm not asking you to do the payment. First of all, I'm telling you, please do a sign-up here, and why I prefer? Because you'll be getting this 15 credits. So, for this 15 credits, I know a lot of… our majorly, all the practicals that I'll be doing will be executed here.
Krish NAik: Okay, and what I will do, I will be sharing you studios. Can you see here there is an option of sharing studios here?
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, I will try to create a public studio, and then I can… it means that you will be directly getting the code through Studios Access. Like, if I show you, published, just wait. I think they have some,
Krish NAik: Version of that.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, templates, if I go. Okay, so here you have, different types of templates, like OpenClaw, this is your… so these are pre-built…
Krish NAik: templates. It means that the code is already there, you have to just go, you have to connect it, and you can start working. Can you see agent interact with pointv3?
Krish NAik: Okay, so people are actually building this, and it's actually easy to share with others. It has got a lot of tutorials, if you guys are really interested, like VLLM with RAG. So a lot of things are there where people are actually doing custom deployment of models.
Krish NAik: And this gives you… it means that they have a dedicated FastAPI server. In one click, HTTP is done.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, like, my… so that's why I would suggest everyone, start with the first step, please do a sign up today, Lightning AI, explore a little bit of the platform. It's pure VS Code, you can install any extension, okay, or in the command line, you have complete command line access, you can install anything.
Krish NAik: Kubernetes, Docker, a complete, like, a power developer, I can say. You are not restricted like Kolar.
Krish NAik: So, please provide a confirmation that everybody is getting this $15. I did. 15 is not coming. 15, I can see. This is 15, not dollar, these are credits, guys. Okay, these are credits, not $15.
Krish NAik: Got credits, okay? Guys, when you are typing, try to, okay, alright, not getting 15 with office meal. You should get, actually, because I feel that office meals, you can actually
Krish NAik: Work with that.
Krish NAik: Because I think they're just PW process, yeah, if you need.
Krish NAik: In some accounts, a dual-gipit can be a problem, but in this account also, this is a company account.
Krish NAik: Okay, in that company account also, I'm getting 14.66. Generally, I feel that company accounts will get… it might take some time to do the verification, but be sure that by this week, because from Saturday, then directly I will start working here.
Krish NAik: The things which is possible to do in collab.
Krish NAik: I will tell, do it in collab, because those are direct notebooks that I can easily share, and you guys can execute. But there are a few things which is not possible, and here you actually have a dedicated space also. The main problem, in Google Collab, like, you have to use the drive and others. Here, no such Tribe. Every time you get an attached. Receive the credits, right?
Krish NAik: Vipen is telling I logged in with the free one, alright? See, like, once the verification is done, everybody will be getting 15. So I feel that, at least for next week, you don't need to pay anything.
Krish NAik: After that week, also, you don't need to pay anything. So, 2 weeks, I'm planning to, explore a lot of things from Multirac, which is not even from your service. And I think, like, other important, because of the war, even I have canceled my foreign trips, okay? So, like.
Krish NAik: I have more time. So, April and May, first week, I can do an extension, and I can discuss more topics. So, like, my focus will be much more on that. Because my plan was to fly out, but because of the war, I'm not going.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So,
Krish NAik: a little bit multimodal stuff, I want to discuss much more, but that is the main. So, once I feel that this gets exhausted, then only do the pain.
Krish NAik: Okay, otherwise, you guys, if you want to create a team or something like that, okay, in that way, but it becomes a pain, rather than having the infrastructure with you. Okay, now you can actually search, because I have not really searched that, which is the best alternate of Lightning AI.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can do your own search, and you can tell me, Paul, that, okay, I'm using this, that is also. Now, from here, I'm giving you your choice that, yes, because I'll be sharing the code in GitHub. Your job is to do a Git clone, set up the repo, I will be sharing all the scripts with you, all those bash scripts to set up those environments. You just have to be sure that… Now, somebody might say that, yes, I have the
Krish NAik: unlimited access to GPUs from my office. So, yes, for R&D stuff, I can actually use my office stuff. If somebody is there, okay, they can let me know, then for them, I will create those scripts. For example, in SageMaker, if you are using. Okay, fine, like, your company's pay, it's great. Okay, then in that case, to do that particular setup. That is also fine with me.
Krish NAik: Okay, the idea is that you do bare minimum payments.
Krish NAik: Okay? I hope everybody understands the core objective.
Krish NAik: Yes, like, people I know, that's why I'm telling you, why then why you guys will be paying for Lightning, who have access to complete cloud GPUs from your office, and you know that I can do R&. The main thing is R&D.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Because the thing, it's not like that anything's secured. It's pretty much inside a particular VM, so other things won't be affected.
Krish NAik: So, totally, like, you guys can let me know, based on that only, like, I'll be creating the repo for those scripts. So, like, if somebody has access to Vertex AI, okay, then in Azure or SageMaker, you can use GPUs, that's really great. Don't pay a single penny, but people who don't have access to anything.
Krish NAik: you need something. So start with Lightning, okay? My job is to make it much more accessible, so my first preference will be collab. So I can say next week, few things I can show you in collab, but next to next week.
Krish NAik: not possible in collab. Okay, it is possible, but again, like, you have to pay in collab $10.
Krish NAik: Okay, but again, later on.
Krish NAik: a lot of things that won't be good. So, that's why. It means somewhere you will get stuck. So, by next week, just be sure that you guys at least sign up into Lightning, and through your OfficeML, you got these credits.
Krish NAik: Okay? Everyone?
Krish NAik: please do a sign-up today only. The verification might take 2 hours, 3 hours, 4 hours, something like that. If the verification is not done, go to Twitter directly, post a tweet. Tell now the verification is not done. Their team is very active in doing that. Okay, I'm telling from my personal experience that, so…
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, it's showing 83 hours of GPU, exactly correct. 83 hours of GPU… see, actually, the GPU that they are telling you, 80 hours. You have to… that is the bare minimum GPU it provides, okay? Actually, if you switch to a better GPU, that, 80 hours become, like, 40 hours instantly.
Krish NAik: Okay, so don't, think.
Krish NAik: With business account and SSO, it is done 15 credits less.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, that's why, like, next week I'll be starting this, part, okay? Because the notebooks are there with me, Minorio and other setup, because I feel that I'll be working a lot with, 24GB of RAM. 16GB, yes, for few things it's possible.
Krish NAik: But not for everything.
Krish NAik: I need that, at least. If I have 48GB of RAM, I feel that I can show you everything. But, if I, then I have to avoid a lot of things, then probably a lot of things might be missed.
Krish NAik: Should we select free or L40S? See, L40S is not required for every practical.
Krish NAik: the only L40 is there. Okay, so, like, L40 versus L40S. There are two different versions of the GPU.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, in some cases, I feel that the L40 standard actually can do the job, okay? But in some cases, I need, the L40H. L40H is the safest, I can say, standard.
Krish NAik: This, actually masked computed also a good one. I don't know. A lot of, masked…
Krish NAik: They also give you proper VM-based instances.
Krish NAik: Businesses.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is also a good one, but I don't love their EUI and other stuff so much. Okay.
Krish NAik: They give you just GPUs, but that entire coding infrastructure, VS code and everything, okay, that is not being handled.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why there are so many providers right now in the market.
Krish NAik: Bye.
Krish NAik: They're sold.
Krish NAik: So, Lightning will be my main preference that I will be using from next class. So, Google Collab and Lightning, I feel, for our initial demos, it will work really great. There won't be any type of issues, but once we start facing the issues, then we will switch directly to,
Krish NAik: this particular studio, okay? And then, like, we can keep separate studios for each GPU. Like, my project studio will be different, as you know, that I'll be creating for every task a separate studio in that way, and just delete the studio once you have done it.
Krish NAik: Because the code will be entirely in GitHub, so at any point of time, you can take a quick clone of that, and you can…
Krish NAik: Can you give us something to try on Lightning today?
Krish NAik: Lightning.
Krish NAik: Alright, okay, Jatinar, you are asking?
Krish NAik: You can take this notebook for now.
Krish NAik: I think.
Krish NAik: So, just to eat. Okay, not this one, I think.
Krish NAik: This is the top dealsman of the company.
Krish NAik: medium totals.
Krish NAik: Absolutely.
Krish NAik: This is with Pool Valley, this will even run in, collab also, but you can try to do the same replication in there.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'm sharing this link because, very similar setup, that even. Just be sure, don't execute all the cells, okay, just be sure when you are executing the stuff. This is Pool Pali, and PoolKali is actually based on pool birth.
Krish NAik: If you remember, I discussed Cool, but the same thing next week, I'll be talking about the architecture of cool value.
Krish NAik: Okay, and like, Manuel is there, a great developer, he always keep update with respect. A lot of papers are there with respect to Pool Pali, but I'll be talking about that. For image-based retrieval, really one of the best options in the market. But Pulpali is an older one. There are bettas right now, like Cold,
Krish NAik: Quinn Vigil is there. Okay, so we'll be working according to 2026 standards. I think Gold Pali came around 2024, okay? So, a few things are deprecated, but at least you can have a test.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, if you have this notebook, and simply, if you are actually going at, I'm just telling you a rough
Krish NAik: setup, okay? So, let's take a new studio, okay?
Krish NAik: I'm just telling a rough setup so that everybody… if you have the credits, you can do it. Otherwise, later on, explore. It's not necessary, because I'm not teaching, rather than the execution example, I'm showing.
Krish NAik: interruptible instance, never take that. What happens in an interruptible instance? In between your work, if there is some type of issue, okay, the instance will be closed.
Krish NAik: Okay, but what is the added benefit? Here, in Lightning, they actually save your work.
Krish NAik: In other platforms, nobody saved your work. And they automatically switch to a cheaper one. You can see, the cost of interruptible instances are very, very cheap.
Krish NAik: But, like, when you were working, I feel that please use, non-interruptible instances, they are better. So let's, pick up something around L4. L4 is a safer site, 24GB.
Krish NAik: Okay, L4, this is from GCP. Actually, I feel that the GCP instances are a little bit slower.
Krish NAik: Okay, but GCP is now cheaper. Always look into who is providing cheaper, and always select that. GCP is providing an AWS. Can you see a huge range difference? So let's go with GCP.
Krish NAik: Okay, and let's confirm. Vision model is fine. I will start the GPU model.
Krish NAik: So always, look into that way, like, who is providing the cheapest one, and based on that, please do the selection.
Krish NAik: How do Vision AI work? Vision AI?
Krish NAik: In Vision AI, exactly what? Vision AI is a very naive term. Under Vision AI, CNL scarms… okay, Transformers comes number one.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: I don't need this agent. They have integrated an agent also, but I don't need their agents. If I want, I can set up codecs or Cloud directly in the terminal.
Krish NAik: Actually, when I work in this, people who are having bigger monitors, okay, switch to bigger monitors, because this screen really feels small to me for a development purpose.
Krish NAik: Okay, for a demo, I have to show you button.
Krish NAik: So, right now, like, the system is launching, like, 60% getting a machine ready. Now, what I will do, I'll be just uploading the notebook, which I have in my… from my local, to here, okay? And they have a dedicated
Krish NAik: like, team space. In the free version, also, you'll be getting a team space. Actually, like, you can connect with S3 buckets.
Krish NAik: S3, if you are actually using your S3 buckets, or directly you can drag and drop, that option is also there. So this is really good.
Krish NAik: for developers.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, fine. Satish, if you're getting 14.98, that is also fine.
Krish NAik: Like, it will be 14.98 or 15 close to that Satish. Okay? So, not…
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, does creating a studio start using my free credits? Exactly, Bill?
Krish NAik: everybody, like, at least do the setup, okay, and let's see, like, what are the things which are available here. I will try to do the replication here once. Exactly the notebook.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see here, this is main.py.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this is green color. Green color means done.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you can see here, print hello, I do need this script.
Krish NAik: Okay, allow… okay, and you can do rest of the stuff, like rename and everything, like a pure VSport stuff. Now, what I will go, I will go to this team space, right?
Krish NAik: And you can actually switch in one click, you can switch to VS Code. In one click, you can switch to Jupyter Notebooks. Can you see here, Windsurf ID? Cursor ID? See, I'm telling you, like, how much powerful it is. If you guys want to feel that, okay, I have my cursor, okay, I can bring cursor quickly in one click.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm telling you.
Krish NAik: Okay, when I, suggest this, okay, there are a lot of, reasons, like, I have actually tested it, and a lot of other integrations that can be done, like coding IDs, VS Code JupyterLab, for training batch jobs, multi-machine training.
Krish NAik: Tensor Boat integrations are there. Okay, for serving, like, API Builder and Lightning deploy really good.
Krish NAik: In Lightning, they have a very dedicated package, just like FastAPI.
Krish NAik: Okay, through, like,
Krish NAik: That also… okay, it is called a sleder. I have used it a lot back in, 2024. And 2025 for that. Okay, now this is much better than FastAPI. This is a minimal framework, very fast. If you're really working with PyTorch.
Krish NAik: I feel this is really good. Okay, but again, like PO, now these type of things, really, in this course, I don't want to focus a lot. Probably in the advanced version, I'll be taking up these things and show you for deployment-level optimizations. But not right now, this is not. Yes, now I think, where is my…
Krish NAik: Gpu instance.
Krish NAik: where I launch the GPU, man, when I get confused a lot.
Krish NAik: Just with lightning.
Krish NAik: Just now, I launched an instance. Where is the instance?
Krish NAik: Hmm?
Krish NAik: Next to Paul Pali, even I got confused, so many tabs I have opened. Just wait, let me remove the unwanted ones. To the other unwanted.
Krish NAik: Here I'm not used. I failed that I used it in that account only. This is the work account.
Krish NAik: Mmm, where I am now.
Krish NAik: Really got confused. Let's stop, let's stop. Okay, yeah, this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, from this, let me get the, GPU, okay? So, what I will do, just for…
Krish NAik: I think I can recommend this one, gold pile, okay?
Krish NAik: I've already shared the link with you guys, so you guys can download the link.
Krish NAik: I have not kept it in GitHub, so I cannot do a direct git clone, I hope everybody understands. So, manually, like, everything, you can upload it here. So, git clone feature is there, and
Krish NAik: I've already showed you in class also, I think anybody… I think in your batch, somebody tested it out. I think Saurabh was there, Saurabh Verma, again, a few other people tested, Lightning previously, and Drag Batch also.
Krish NAik: No, that's not this month.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, add data. So, from here, actually, I can go to my studios. This studio, okay, and here, actually, I can, add and drop. So, let me just open my, this is the one. Okay, so let me just,
Krish NAik: Try to do a drag-and-drop multimodal with full value.
Krish NAik: Okay, it will take some time to upload.
Krish NAik: I think under 1 minute, it is majorly done.
Krish NAik: If you have something in your S3, can you see it is available?
Krish NAik: The file is available. Okay, now let me get back here.
Krish NAik: to VS Code.
Krish NAik: Okay, some type of authentication, I think. Well, like, it's, just opened a separate, window. If you feel that… because I feel that this window is much better to work with, as compared to seeing, so many things.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you can actually install it also, so this option is also there, install Lightning Studio. So later on, I'll be talking. For me, this is not so much about it.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me just open the new terminal from here.
Krish NAik: I think, is this the one connection, Gemini?
Krish NAik: No, I don't remember, yes. So, let me check whether I have the GPU connected or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you can see you have that 23 GB, I can see, like, 23.
Krish NAik: 24GB, out of that, I have accessible close to 23GB of stuff. Fine. Works good. Now, let's start with the installation part. So, from here, what I can do. So, I think, few other packages that I need, actually.
Krish NAik: I need transformers.
Krish NAik: Let me just install all the packages, first of all.
Krish NAik: Transformers, and then I think I need, accelerate, I need accelerate, accelerate, accelerators.
Krish NAik: Beautiful.
Krish NAik: These things come straight-installed and collapsed, so I have removed, actually, from them.
Krish NAik: Now, okay, let me do the installation of this package as well.
Krish NAik: Okay, Paul, please share the collab link once, okay? You are asking for the collab link.
Krish NAik: I think just wait, I… it will be in my chat only, just wait.
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: Whenever you are pasting, guys, in your chat, always check the setting that everyone or host or panelists.
Krish NAik: In that way, Satish, like, you pasted it, but it's actually, looking to…
Krish NAik: Okay, why it doesn't get pasted here?
Krish NAik: means… Alright, yes, I have shared the collab with you.
Krish NAik: to everything.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, this is, basically a check that whether the libraries are available or not.
Krish NAik: when, VLutils, I just installed, I think, when VLutils…
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, I can say it's there, actually, okay? So that's fine.
Krish NAik: I don't need to do any of these installations for now.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let me install the most important thing. So, pip installed, BialDe, Kolpale Engine, Pillow, and Google Gen AI. So, in this one, I think I'll be working with, Google API. Yeah, so pretty much easy to work with. Let me do the installation of these packages. So, through Kolpali Engine, I will be accessing Kolpali.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this is done. Okay, package installation also done. Okay, now let me try to, okay. Now, see, here I need a .env file. Now, this is the other problem. How many of you know that .env in Google Cloud?
Krish NAik: Then, manually, you have to do that, so here, actually, I can create a .env file.
Krish NAik: Okay, and let me just get, that is the other problem of collab. You have to pass everything to their secret manager, or manually create that ENB file through touch, okay, you have to get done. Now, just let me open, I think, somewhere there, I'll be having access to.
Krish NAik: The Google API key.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is John.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now, I think HF token is not required in this case, so let me see right now. If it asks, then only I will set.
Krish NAik: Alright, I can see the execution is successful. Let me see…
Krish NAik: Okay, so 8GB of model, that is getting downloaded. Everyone, please have a check.
Krish NAik: And the… I feel that sometimes the free version of collab internet speed is also very bad.
Krish NAik: Like, in collab, the free version means just thing that
Krish NAik: Not so many things that can be possible, okay? So it's telling that, alright, it has been done.
Krish NAik: Now, you can, actually, like,
Krish NAik: get anyone. Here, I've kept the attention is all you people. Okay, so here, WGATE, MKDI, MV. I think these commands are pretty much self-explanatory to everyone.
Krish NAik: And, if you're not sure about in which place you are, always look into PWD. See, guys.
Krish NAik: please use more Linux commands in that way. So, you can see this studio. So, this studio is the main folder name. Alright. Now,
Krish NAik: let me download the paper, because on top of this paper, I'll be applying that. Okay, so the paper is downloaded, and it is inside my docs folder. Attention is all you need.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the paper is available. Now, I'll be working with the OCR. For OCR in Linux, you need popular utils. I think you guys have already worked with Poplar. How many of you remember?
Krish NAik: I know that you guys have installed Popular in class.
Krish NAik: For Windows, also, there is a dedicated, poplar
Krish NAik: And so it's the same thing that I'm doing at Linux.
Krish NAik: Alright, Asma, see, the verification in Lightning AI takes time.
Krish NAik: That's why I told you. If it doesn't work, write a tweet in Twitter. Their team will try to handle it.
Krish NAik: Okay, now sudo apt gate update and install, let me do the installation of this package here.
Krish NAik: We'll get bye.
Krish NAik: Now, this is, like, just wait. I don't want to, because here, I think CO tends…
Krish NAik: Because this is a Docker one, so I think in Docker one,
Krish NAik: If I take the pseudo-access, let me see.
Krish NAik: Because I think this is,
Krish NAik: I got zero credits with Eduum. Really, I've not… never signed up with an Eduum.
Krish NAik: But, have a check-in. I domail. If you want me to sign up, I can do that, Venka.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I can tell you.
Krish NAik: Now, let me check the rag.indexinges.
Krish NAik: Okay, so actually I need to update this path, let me copy the relative, allow, copy relative path, let me paste it here. Okay, I think it should work. Okay, store collection with index, the default one.
Krish NAik: Now, the speeds that you'll be getting here will be much better as compared to collab, okay? Now, this in collab, 1, 2, 3, 4, if you try to do the same stuff in collab, you will understand. See, this tutorial, I'm doing at Lightning.ai, but you guys can actually, like, use it.
Krish NAik: Okay, can you see here, by D, this folder? Okay, I'm using this folder, everything that gets created, so this is, like, the main collection, then comes your embeddings.pt, everything is in PyTorch file, okay?
Krish NAik: Now, this is the biology package file. Now, this got executed, so now, if I try to ask a question from the table… okay, now this is the question that I'm asking. What is the blue score of transformer base mode? This is the query.
Krish NAik: Okay, and later on, I think I can increase the search amount.
Krish NAik: Okay, let's look into the results.
Krish NAik: I just execute all the files, and later on, I think it will do.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you will actually see in that document exactly where is the information.
Krish NAik: And from here, transformers base model, 27.3 and 38.1. Now, this information, if you want to print it out, this is my Gemini key. Use my key also, it's the free key, I am not worried about that. So…
Krish NAik: And I think I can, print it on.
Krish NAik: Okay, please do have a check. 27.3 and 38.1.
Krish NAik: 27.3 and 38.1. These are the actual blue scores. Can you see, like, how efficient it is, everyone.
Krish NAik: the same practical, you can execute it in Google Collab. Also, people who don't have access to it execute it in collab. Later on, once you get the access to Lightning, please do that. Okay, but for the purpose of this particular tutorial, use sudo, sudo, sudo melon.
Krish NAik: Just add that sudo access.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, like, this is really good, so this is just a demo for, Kulpali that I was telling. Okay? So, I have shared the API key, just be sure you use yours, okay?
Krish NAik: Actually, I have to delete the key, this is connected with my credit card.
Krish NAik: This is a paid account that I have. Okay, so… find app, share the key, I will delete it.
Krish NAik: I think.
Krish NAik: So I've shown you the demo, so just wait, let me delete the key first of all.
Krish NAik: I forgot it, it actually just connected with my, account already.
Krish NAik: Because later on, I thought I will switch to that, one, but,
Krish NAik: For our initial testing, we've done it.
Krish NAik: get an API key… Okay, I think, March 14th, this is the one, I'm deleting it here.
Krish NAik: Okay, as you can see, this is mine.
Krish NAik: Well, there is no such Jesus.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody please do test it out, I have showed you. And please let me know that in Lightning, somebody is asking how to upload.
Krish NAik: click on this option, up Team Space Drive, okay, and from Team Space Drive, go to that studio, like this studio, majorly, like, with the name. This studio will come, and from that studio, you can directly, like, click on the upload option.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the first option that you have, which is the team space, right?
Krish NAik: Here, you can actually do connection with S3 buckets and others, but for now, keep it minimal.
Krish NAik: Amar is telling I got the email from to office and clicked to confirm as well, still not allowing me to log in.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, in the another batch, I know that there was one student.
Krish NAik: Okay, what he did, he created, I think, 3 accounts for, Lightning E, from 3 different email IDs.
Krish NAik: Okay, but that way he got 15, 15, 15, 45 credits, and he actually did a lot of stuff. That is the other work way around. But, really, like, whichever way you feel.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. You can connect their, support at the right lighting, they are telling invalid number, support code, alright. How did you start all of this, Jatindra? Exactly, like, what you told… how did you start? What did I start? I put wrong time.
Krish NAik: Yes, with Gmail account, you won't be getting any credit, it actually takes… I even don't use with any Gmail account.
Krish NAik: I always work with organizational accounts.
Krish NAik: I think, which account is this one? This one is the consultant account that I have.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please be sure, and you get 200 GB. 200 GB is more than… okay, so excess, so, like, most of your work, I know 100, 200 GB will be done for this.
Krish NAik: See, once you have L Studios, this studio, from here you can upload the file. Can you see Add Data Option, or directly drag and drop?
Krish NAik: Okay, whichever option you feel, you can proceed ahead with that.
Krish NAik: So for, okay, here you can add anything. So, that's the best thing, and in one click, you can switch to your VS port. So, it is… the development is easy, the debugging is easy.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, another thing, why I prefer this with respect to my deployments, like, you know that in other places, like, I have to always switch from my
Krish NAik: what I can say. Like, if I run a simple HTTP, okay, just let me get a, I think ChatGPT, where is ChatGPT? I will just get a, FastAPI boilerplate for now, okay? Just wait.
Krish NAik: I think they have the Asian mode.
Krish NAik: Let me… I'm not used, really.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think this was the one. Which one is the agent module?
Krish NAik: Okay, AI co-pilot, Chris.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Create a file, fastapi underscore app dot py, okay, with the bare minimum
Krish NAik: route, a single route, okay, and hello world route only. Okay, the idea is to just do the testing of the fast API route is working or not. When I hit the route, it should be only Hello World coming.
Krish NAik: Okay, so create a file, fast AP underscore, bare minimum, everything came here. Fine, let me just,
Krish NAik: remove this particular context, I actually don't need this particular context, but I mean…
Krish NAik: How the hell can I remove… I think it is opened in the other file, that's why it should.
Krish NAik: Fine, let me just take the prove that.
Krish NAik: I'm just creating the file, just to show you, like, with respect to the port viewer option, it's really great.
Krish NAik: Alright, so you can see here, you can, run the FastAPI application, FastAPI. I think the file should be created by now. File, file, file, file, file, FastAPI, FastAPI.
Krish NAik: Where is the file?
Krish NAik: machine…
Krish NAik: It's telling it's created, but where is the phi?
Krish NAik: Mmm, they're gone.
Krish NAik: Okay? Apply.
Krish NAik: Is it taking some time? Okay, yes, fast API key. Okay, as you can see, this is a simple route. Now, just think about if I want to host it, online. So, what I will do, let's go here, let's open new terminal.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it's telling that, first of all, install, FastAPI in Recon. Fine, let me do the installations here.
Krish NAik: Okay, requirement already. Satisfied, great. Now, let me start the server at this one, okay? Alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, UVicon Fast API app, app, app, host, port, 8000. 8000 is the default one, let me run.
Krish NAik: Okay, can you see here the server is running? Now, the idea is that how to make it as a public HD. So, I think, from here…
Krish NAik: you have this port viewer option. You can actually go to this port viewer. You can click on new port. Okay, and let me write here fast API. Okay, and the port number is 8000. Okay, so add.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is, mine one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now it's telling that, okay, let's open the public link.
Krish NAik: Can you repeat?
Krish NAik: what is the added benefit of this one? Because really, like, during my development, really, I need to test out the API that I'll be building while my project. Can you see exactly how quickly I got that part?
Krish NAik: So that way, for development purpose, that's why I'm suggesting. It's not like that I have not done other platform research around Boat and others.
Krish NAik: not so much developer-friendly. They are really thought from developer perspective.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's one. Like, other things, they have done direct integrations, which Streamlit also, if you're working with Streamlit, I think, somewhere will be there, the Streamlit part.
Krish NAik: data, I think under Web Apps it will come. Streamlead, React, Gradio. Okay, this code here that I am using right now for custom applications.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, really, the options are really great. Okay, and for initial testing, it's good. So that's why I told you, like, use whichever way, okay, everything is there, cars are windshield users, okay, so I don't think there will be any particular problem that you'll be facing.
Krish NAik: I think, how many of you executed the notebook that I have shared? Please let me.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: How many of… or how many of you, the execution worked, really? Like,
Krish NAik: Just wait, where is that,
Krish NAik: Even I get kind of pussy, yes, here it is. Yes, please let me know for how many of you it worked.
Krish NAik: Can you show where I can see plugins, alright? Plugins, you will see here. This plus option is there, no?
Krish NAik: add plugins to extend the studio functionality. This plus option is available.
Krish NAik: No credits blocked.
Krish NAik: I really see. I'm not sure, like, why, because I feel with office email, bankrupt, I will come. Okay, don't worry, because I've never tested with a .adoo email, but I don't have any other office email. In all of my office emails, I have
Krish NAik: Like, nick.ai signed up. In one account, it is actually blocked.
Krish NAik: Okay? In one of my Gmail accounts, it's actually blocked, that's it.
Krish NAik: Chaitan that you are asking, okay, I am telling, people use like me.
Krish NAik: Okay, because behind the scenes, I am telling, it is available through their marketplace.
Krish NAik: For developers, okay, I'm just telling you, AWS, I know, because I was working for a client, I told them, now, directly they won't purchase Lightning, your point is time. You have to access it through your AWS credentials.
Krish NAik: That's why. It's the other way around, through a marketplace app.
Krish NAik: Okay, the same thing, you can do it in an organization. See, in organization, it's not about saving money, you have to understand. Use SageMaker blindly. I'm not talking about using this platform. My job is to make your tutorial much more easier, so that you can do it. I hope you get my…
Krish NAik: I can use a Scene Maker Studio, but that is very costly, whereas this type of platform is much easier to work with.
Krish NAik: They have an enterprise account also, that's what, Mundas said.
Krish NAik: Okay, and direct enterprise to enterprise are there.
Krish NAik: For a Dubai client, I actually did the entire development setup in, like.
Krish NAik: Because their product was based on, image.
Krish NAik: And for image and videos, you need dedicated clusters. So, for developers, Lightning is good. The development is done in Lightning. Later on, the entire deployment pipeline, gets switched to AWS.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is for development. Nobody does deployment here. Again, I am repeating myself. This is for development. Nobody does deployment here. Is this part clear? You can do the deployment, but the pricing is very high.
Krish NAik: Okay? This is for development purpose.
Krish NAik: Alright, flash attention you don't need if you have checked the recent notebook that I have told.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Please do have a check on the recent versions. Recent, recent, recent.
Krish NAik: Where is that, notebook, I think, in this notebook. So, from there, remove flash attention, and please use this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, don't execute this cell. Don't execute this cell. This cell is not required, Hanji. You just need the first cell.
Krish NAik: And, in Collab, Transformers and Accelerate comes by default. Okay, so I haven't installed that. If you are doing it, please do the installation of Transformers and Accelerate.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you want, let me just share it here. It's, my notebook.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the command data execute attempt.
Krish NAik: Do we have to create requirement.txt? No, no, no, no, there is no requirement.txt.
Krish NAik: The installation of the required packages are available in the cells.
Krish NAik: So, really, you don't need.
Krish NAik: So, I hope everybody gets, like, why I'm suggesting
Krish NAik: Lightning, from our development perspective, it will be much easier. Because, like, once I have fixed, my development pipeline is fixed, later on everything, like, whether AWS, that's the other stuff around, that we can figure it out. But for our initial development, it should be fast.
Krish NAik: Collab doesn't give you that fast experience. Here, you will feel that, yeah, the speeds are very good.
Krish NAik: As compared to data.
Krish NAik: I didn't find the links, I had really not added any links in Notion.
Krish NAik: Abhi Jayit, because this is just, like Jatinda suggested, we want to play out in lightning, so I just shared the collab. I have really not taught you what is Kulpali, how it is similar to Kulbat.
Krish NAik: Okay, those things really. So, next Saturday I'll be talking about, but right now, the main idea is to do the setup, and I want to inform you that, yes.
Krish NAik: That initial one or two classes, you can do it in the free trial, but at some point, you need to move into
Krish NAik: A paid one.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you, are not getting… because I know there are students, like, who create, like, 3 different Lightning AI accounts, that's why I told you. I met one student there. He was… but every time it doesn't happen. From… if you create multiple accounts from the same IP, if you try to hit it, they might block your account also. That also becomes a problem.
Krish NAik: I bet.
Krish NAik: need the docs folder that I have kept the code there to create the docs folder. Please do check out the code, everyone, I've already shared. Here I'm doing MKDR docs, guys.
Krish NAik: Rajat.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, please let me know that, according to you, that the development is easy or not here, as compared to collab, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because Event Collab comes with some free credits, limited usage.
Krish NAik: But, yes, you guys can let me know.
Krish NAik: your experience. Amar is asking if the blockers will unblock… no, no, no, one of my accounts got blocked, never it got unblocked yet.
Krish NAik: I think this is only the account that got blocked. Let me show you my main account, the free one here, this one, yes.
Krish NAik: This account only. Can you see here, if I go, can you see red color 000?
Krish NAik: This account actually, like, it got blocked, because in this account, I have used nothing.
Krish NAik: Okay, I cannot use, neither day. Every month, you get 15 credits. Every month, by default.
Krish NAik: But in this account, I don't get. In the other account, I get.
Krish NAik: Which is the office email account, that's fine.
Krish NAik: Gmail will never work, only use Office emails, that's the only thing. Later on, I will come to you, Ammar, okay, and I think, Venkatesh was there. I will look into your issues, but, for now, for today's sake, just, work on the practicals part. Okay, because from next week, then, I will try to use
Krish NAik: I think only next week it is possible to do it in Google Collab, because this granite was also not, working, really good, I can say.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this pipeline was also not working really well. Like, I felt that I need at least, 24 GB and others.
Krish NAik: Only till Olpali, to a certain extent, I can keep it, but later on, it is not possible.
Krish NAik: So that's why a rough idea that I have shared with you guys, okay, and from next week. Because I'll be telling you some questions, that's why, like,
Krish NAik: If the block is for me, Gmail is working. Okay, for Rohit, for you, Gmail is working great.
Krish NAik: Again, mixed reviews that we can build.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, I just shared a single collab link. Nothing I have shared, Abhijit. It's just to get started with Lightning, that was the main agenda. And always remember to switch off your studio. This is very, very important if you are actually using Lightning, whether the free, whether the paid.
Krish NAik: What happens? You might forget, and you will tell, wow, okay, I forgot, actually, to close the studio. Okay, now this is a running state. Always, like,
Krish NAik: I think… not this account, I have created it from which account?
Krish NAik: Not this account, this account, yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, always go to your home. If you want, kill the studio. So here you can see this one. So here you have the option of studio environment. Okay, so please make the studio scene. In that way, once you, again, switch it on, you will have access to all of your data.
Krish NAik: Okay? And if you don't want the access, simply you can see saving state,
Krish NAik: Or simply, like, you can click here, and you can do… if you don't want the studio anymore, if your work is done, delete the studio.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please always, like, keep it in sleep mode, delete it if you don't need it, don't think that, okay, I have switched on, and my credit's own me. So, just be sure about, this is very, very important for free users also.
Krish NAik: If you forget everything, like, you know that, like, if you forget for 10 hours, also, all of your credits will be exhausted.
Krish NAik: How will you check the Fast API? Alright, I will come to you already.
Krish NAik: I have done in sleep mode, okay, so I don't be showing. You can't raise your hand behind, I will be showing.
Krish NAik: Alright, okay, so now, as I have done, I will just delete the studio, I don't need the studio anymore. So, let me just right here, delete.
Krish NAik: A very similar infrastructure in our last organization, although we built it.
Krish NAik: Docker-based, but very costly infrastructure.
Krish NAik: If you don't have good clients, then.
Krish NAik: Stop sharing. All right, now, let's, look into a few.
Krish NAik: Delete, delete, Satish, you don't need it, no. Whenever, you can create anytime, so why keep it in sleep mode also? Because for your storage, then few, amount in the credits, that will be picked.
Krish NAik: Okay, so Amar Melind,
Krish NAik: and project. People who have questions with respect to GPUs, any stuff, you can ask me today, because today's class, it will be much more from the
Krish NAik: perspective of, infrastructure, those things, okay. And I think I have already shared the project emails. I think people have responded also in their mail loops. That discussion, even I forgot today, like, AWS and Azure groups, I have created it. In GCP, only, I think, 5 or 6 people told.
Krish NAik: So, really, like, I could not get at least, 10 or 13 people in that. But for Azure and AWS groups, I have shared it, so the leads, just try to have a meet. Set up your, like, communication channel, like,
Krish NAik: Discord or anything, and however you love it, because I… it's totally up to you and the team member's decision. I have no personal choices, so do the setup. Once, at least do an initial meeting. I think the AWS team already has that, so at least, the architecture, please, leaders decide it.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think 33 leads I have given. Take your time out, today, or whenever you work. So, I am given 8 weeks time. Okay, I think 8 weeks is enough, yes or no, for that project.
Krish NAik: Because with AI, if you are really coding, I feel that 8 weeks… is enough. Yes?
Krish NAik: Not everybody, I only selected handpicked. Out of, I think, 60 people filled out the form.
Krish NAik: I think only 26 students I have selected. Once the project is done, then I will ask the team to present and showcase that entire project. It's not like everybody I have picked up. Majorly, one field was there, why you want to join that particular project?
Krish NAik: Okay, that field, I've actually focused, and I actually looked into people who are actually working, aligning. It's not about learning. Here, the main purpose is not. Once the project is quickly developed, then, these guys can do the discussion.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's the main objective. The development should be faster, so I've actually picked up only those people who have already worked, working currently. Okay, so that's so in that.
Amarsrinivas: Hi, Paul.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, I can get it, Shivani. Okay, so it's not like everybody I have picked up, it's only limited group of students.
Krish NAik: Alright, yes.
Amarsrinivas: Hi, Paul.
Krish NAik: This is a new RAG-only date, because every organization needs external data, but a little bit changes will be there. In the agent's part, I will say that
Krish NAik: Probably with respect to local file systems access, that is getting widely popular, AgentFS, that we call it. That part, even I will teach you, in class, don't worry.
Krish NAik: Once, right now, my major focus is, see, Langrap and other things, not so much, but actually, multimodal is much tougher. Langrap, if you spend 8 hours, easily anyone can learn, it's easy. So, agents part, I've kept it. I feel that till first.
Krish NAik: week of April, we'll be exploring multimodal. In multimodal, once we have that, then I think, because if few people want to work on the NVIDIA-based project, you can let me know. Then, I can…
Krish NAik: take a…
Krish NAik: enterprise account, and then in that way, a small group I can create, and you can actually work on the NVIDIA AI Blueprint, if anybody is interested. But after 1st April, I will plan for that. In the meantime, the other two groups which are assigned with AWS and Azure part.
Krish NAik: you guys, so a separate team for NVIDIA stacked that time, because NVIDIA is widely used in the US, you know.
Krish NAik: Like, in India, I feel it is, somehow not used. I don't know what's the problem here.
Krish NAik: But, in US, widely used, in Europe, widely used, the NVIDIA stack. Actually, for enterprise-level,
Krish NAik: production, like, anybody, if you have worked with any NVIDIA stack.
Krish NAik: like, healthcare, they have a separate stack for computer vision, vision analytics, they have a stack, like, deep stream. I used to use… work with Deepstream back in 2019.
Krish NAik: So, like,
Krish NAik: the stack of NVIDIA is really good, but again, Indian organizations, I feel that, really, they don't use NVIDIA, so much.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let's start with the questions. One by one, I will be taking the questions. So Amar, you can start. Milind, Mitesh, Rajat, others also simply raise your hand and communicate.
Amarsrinivas: hi, Paul. Actually, two classes before, you have.
Krish NAik: Once it is done, Subhash, I think. Because… Subhash…
Krish NAik: I don't know, but, yes. I think, just wait, Amar Aman. I think my, speaker is a different one, just wait.
Amarsrinivas: Okay, okay, okay.
Krish NAik: Nice. Yeah, done.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, so, two classes before, you have given a Google Form to fill in. Actually, I missed that class because that week, my son is not well. So, can we also fill again?
Krish NAik: Last week, see, last to last week, I shared, then again in last week I shared.
Krish NAik: It's not like that. Two weeks are actually. In the first week, I think 30 people filled up. In the next one, again, 30 people filled up.
Krish NAik: Because that part is done, I'm not, because now the GCP slot, if people are interested in the GCP part, you can do it. For GCP, let me just… okay, I think I have the email ID, so I cannot share it, but, just wait.
Amarsrinivas: promise to know the, interest in AWS or GCP, or, for any project related.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, there I actually asked that, what is your cloud experience?
Krish NAik: According to that, people who told AWS, I kept them in AWS. Now, Azure, people who told Azure, I kept them in Azure. It's based on your preference. I just picked up that preference. So, Excel, just wait a month.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, because I was more in AWS, that's why.
Krish NAik: Okay, AWS, I think, majorly, GCP only, I feel the least people have responded. I think 5 people were there, only 1 lead was there, so I… actually, just wait, let me just share my screen and show you that. So people, if you want to work with GCP part, I'm fine.
Krish NAik: Like, I can create other team. For that team till now? No, just wait, let me open the sheets once.
Krish NAik: Yeah, often.
Amarsrinivas: This, I want to share my screen and show that error, login error.
Krish NAik: Logging in. Okay, I'm adding. People with, screen sharing, tell me in the chat, I am adding you. Mitesh or Melind, anyone wants to share their screen, please let me know.
Krish NAik: JCP, but, okay, just wait.
Mitesh Shah: Yes.
Krish NAik: Wait, give me one… Mitesh wrote yes, no?
Krish NAik: Okay, I'm adding you two panelists. You guys can do it. Chaitan Jagapati admin is just…
Amarsrinivas: Okay, can I share my screen?
Krish NAik: Mmm.
Krish NAik: Abhijit, today I didn't start multimodal, I just showed you. I think you joined late. Today's session was only deciding the stack.
Krish NAik: Okay, then there is your hand, and I can clarify that. I was talking about, going forward, you need to do that. Here's pretty much the class, because I'm not planning to teach, so much else today.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, Paul, actually, I got the email and I confirmed as well, if you see my screen.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Amarsrinivas: But after that, when I'm trying to log in, it's not allowing me to log in.
Krish NAik: what it's telling. Show me.
Krish NAik: Because, see, these are… directly third-party platforms. Even I have zero idea, like,
Krish NAik: Enter your email. Okay, it's telling… wait for the verification. For some email IDs, it might take 8 hours, 10 hours.
Krish NAik: It's not necessary that it is done instantly.
Amarsrinivas: an office email also.
Krish NAik: Even on office email is much faster as compared to personal email. It means that personal email might take 3 days, this might take 3-4 hours.
Amarsrinivas: Okay. Even when Gmail also having same issue?
Krish NAik: Gmail, I don't suggest, like, Gmail, by default.
Krish NAik: They majorly block Gmail account.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, my main worry is, suppose if by next week, if it is not solved, then I will be…
Krish NAik: I think collab part, you can do it. Otherwise, if you have access to cloud, do it in SageMaker. That is the last option.
Krish NAik: Name, man.
Amarsrinivas: My MacBook is 40-core GPU, will that be sufficient?
Krish NAik: Oh! 40 core GPU, like, which one? Did you have the recent one, M5 Max?
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, last year I bought a MacBooks.
Krish NAik: CRM formats.
Amarsrinivas: Yeah, M4Max.
Amarsrinivas: Do you…
Krish NAik: can do it, but not everything. That's the thing. It's really good. The recent M5 Max that got launched, I think, one week back, that's really… M4 Max, you can do the testing. Okay, I will be sharing the scripts based on Transformers. It means that my, everything I'll be downloading from the Transformers.
Krish NAik: actually, from Hugging Face, I'll be looting the model. You can test it out. 40-core CPUs, it's at least, I can say, to a certain extent. And what is the RAM you have?
Krish NAik: 6 months.
Amarsrinivas: April.
Krish NAik: Okay, 64. Great, then, I think you can do it in your local M formats and works really well. But not everything, you have to understand. Like, out of 7 components, 5 will work, 2 will not work. In that case, switch to API for 2.
Krish NAik: Okay, I will tell you according to your scrap definition.
Krish NAik: Aruna, see, collab paid, I told you, in collab, I don't have access to Docker.
Krish NAik: Already, I told to everyone, collab is for beginners, not for power developers, and I feel that in this course, we have reached that point. We are power developers part.
Krish NAik: Okay. In collab, again, like, exposing, again, I have to install NGRock through that, I have to… a lot of other things. For development purpose, Lightning is much better. I think, Aruna, you're from, educational background, so the same collab
Krish NAik: I think, you are paying, collab, like, $10, the same academic pricing you get for Lightning also, $9, $9.99, $10. Okay, you can use that, because for you, at the end of the day, it's the same. Collab and this.
Krish NAik: Okay, in M4, you can change the settings and increase the performance. Yes, M4 Max, not M4 Pro.
Amarsrinivas: And one last question is,
Amarsrinivas: Is there a batch assigned already for final projects, or normally?
Krish NAik: Batch, assigned a batch, a batch, batch?
Amarsrinivas: I mean, is there a project, a group project will be there, or individual projects only going forward?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no. The five projects that I discussed that I will be doing. That project, the work that I've done is totally separate. It's for community, like, to be told that I want to do this, I want to do this, so based on that only aspect. It's nothing… once they have done the work, now they can showcase their work to me for that later on in the year.
Amarsrinivas: Okay.
Amarsrinivas: Thanks, Harper.
Krish NAik: Bill Justin.
Krish NAik: Because of GCP part, I think I have a few slots left, so… just… let me just show you the sheet also. In the meantime, or Mitesh, I think. Mitesh, you can share your screen, and you can stop sharing.
Krish NAik: Yes, I can show you that one. In GCP, I think, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5. Okay, yeah, they were joking, like, your name is in GCP, like, 5 people I have, because in your experience, I saw that, but I'm looking for a few more people. But in GCP, like, at least
Krish NAik: If you want, I can share it soon.
Krish NAik: Methesh, okay, I'm looking into your screen, but, sorry, okay. I've removed the email IDs, and I'm just showing you the names. I think AWS and Azure already, I've shared the, emails from here.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this was a GCP, okay, I think a few people were there. Here, I have kept those.
Krish NAik: Okay? As mentioned, but I didn't get other people in the form with respect to Jesus.
Krish NAik: I applied filters on prior cloud experience and which one you were interested in. Both GCP were very, very nice.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I felt that If you want later.
Krish NAik: AWS, I'm not adding, I have finalists, okay, doing any changes.
Krish NAik: Because I was planning for two years, but later on, I thought, let's make…
Krish NAik: Alright, so I will stop sharing now…
Krish NAik: It's not for everyone, again, I told you. Ravi…
Krish NAik: I think you are not… your name is not there, neither in EWS, I believe.
Krish NAik: No, see, if you don't have experience in GP, simply say, it's not about exploring. I don't want people to…
Krish NAik: explore and then do it. The idea is that you should have that priority. Based on that one, you have found the teams. And that way, development becomes faster.
Krish NAik: Alright, Mitesh, you are sharing your screen, I can see that, okay? Add sudo.
Krish NAik: at sudo.
Krish NAik: remove APT get update and only write sudo apt install. No, no, no restart, no restart, just write sudo. I'm not getting your audio, I don't know what is the issue.
Krish NAik: But, unmute yourself at least.
Krish NAik: Okay, ask to unmute later.
Mitesh Shah: Yeah, got it.
Mitesh Shah: Am I audible now?
Krish NAik: Yeah, yeah, yeah. APD numbers, just remove that update, I think you don't need to just add that pseudo part.
Krish NAik: Okay, and that… yes, I added now.
Krish NAik: Just delete that, and, and also delete, just do a sudo, and… Yes. Right, sudo?
Krish NAik: After the exclamation mark?
Mitesh Shah: Can you please… This one?
Krish NAik: No, no, sudo a SUDO.
Mitesh Shah: This is a Linux companies.
Krish NAik: Linux, yes, this is entirely your Linux system, so go into it.
Krish NAik: Okay, and keep pseudo with exclamatory sign. Whenever you are working with Jupyter notebooks, it's just like collab. Yes, now hit enter. Shift-Enter.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Mitesh Shah: No idea that you didn't.
Mitesh Shah: I was wondering why…
Mitesh Shah: was going in that direction. Okay, thank you. Just one thing, I think, so people are asking this question, I'm also going to throw that. There is a new course that is coming up, right? From today.
Mitesh Shah: Can you give us an idea on it, so that the RAD batch, whoever joins that course, how it would be useful, and what else will be…
Krish NAik: I am bachelor's student, so let's talk about that also. I think you guys can see my screen? No, no, I'm not sure, understood. Where is that PDF, first of all, letting me search for the PDF?
Krish NAik: I think in the other batch, people were asking, it is good for Gen AI. If, nobody has anything, I think this is the full stack, piece.
Krish NAik: Good. I think, I'm open with everything.
Mitesh Shah: There's one.
Krish NAik: Not this one? Which one was that?
Mitesh Shah: It's, let me search for the.
Krish NAik: Right, so this was his, tarting today.
Mitesh Shah: No, no, not thus far.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Mitesh Shah: other one, might, you know, Sir, if somebody can help.
Mitesh Shah: I don't remember the exact name of it.
Krish NAik: Which one, which one?
Krish NAik: Even I was not this week, so even I am not aware if any new thing that came. Tell me.
Mitesh Shah: Modern route to full-stack generative AI and agility.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, modern… okay, that… okay, even I was… I showed you the wrong video. That's only Sunny's batch.
Mitesh Shah: Yes.
Krish NAik: Modern route, modern route, where is that PDF? I thought I downloaded it, yeah.
Krish NAik: You're sweet.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
Krish NAik: Just wait, this is,
Krish NAik: Rather on this is for fine. This is that syllabus only, no?
Mitesh Shah: Same one? I'm not sure.
Krish NAik: Deliver says, same thing, don't go in the name.
Mitesh Shah: Okay.
Krish NAik: Don't go in the name.
Amarsrinivas: Even, I have same question, for example, our batch will already cover these topics, right?
Krish NAik: A few things are covered, few things are not there, okay, because… but this is good for anybody starting their Gen AI journey.
Krish NAik: Not advanced users. There is a difference between advanced and advanced. So, anybody who feels that, they want to start their Gen AI journey, that's why the name is Full Stack GenAI, and if I show you that, let me just show you. I think this is the same PDF only, but just for your confirmation, this is the courses.
Krish NAik: Just wait, full-stack generative AI bootcamp, can you see?
Krish NAik: the name.
Amarsrinivas: But we can't see all this in our login, poll, actually.
Krish NAik: I am the admin, so why you will see?
Amarsrinivas: No, I don'.
Krish NAik: Baked stuff, no.
Amarsrinivas: At least, it should give you option to pay or explore… check the.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, this comes under subscription. This I'm showing you, this is not that. This is the EI project subscription, so that's why these things are coming.
Krish NAik: Okay, for you as a customer, if I go there…
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the customer one, just wait. I think, that end-to-end, end-to-end, end-to-end, which one is?
Krish NAik: We only made a course overview, I think, this month.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think, the syllabus
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the modern route only, no? Modern route? Yes, can you see the syllabus is this one that I was shown.
Mitesh Shah: But, then the first one was 12 months batch, and this is 6 months batch.
Krish NAik: No, no, that is different. That is the ultimate. There, Python and basic stuff is taught, no? Python, stats, machine learning, those things. Why you need to go in that ratch?
Krish NAik: If you are from a data science background, then you don't need… no, really. This is the Gen AI starters. If anybody's new to Gen AI, for them, this is really good. It has, all the things with respect to Gen AI that, our foundational guys should know.
Krish NAik: Okay, but not, again, for advanced users, like,
Krish NAik: A lot of things are there, which I feel that, yes, which is generic, and it is used even for fine-tuning, but again, for before discussing RHLF, you have to work with certain algorithms, but for a basic startup, I feel that this is really great. LLM hosting on your own server.
Krish NAik: Okay, now,
Krish NAik: like, using run code or something like that, but exactly, I don't know, but he has planned. Okay, so anything that you can do. Now, prompt engineering is pretty much dead. I feel that context engineering is more important. Okay, then comes RAG. Now, whatever the things here in RAG is there, now just… you guys don't need to really work on that RAG stuff.
Krish NAik: Advanced and multimodal system, the thing that I'll be discussing in your upcoming module, that will be a lot more. I think he has added a few things with respect to security.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is same land graph stuff that is there in your batch. Evaluation strategies already, I told about, those things.
Krish NAik: Okay? NLP-based metrics. Garters, this is new, I think. This is the first time we have added that. MCP is pretty much the same module.
Krish NAik: Okay, then cloud services, EIML. Now, this part, can be beneficial to someone, but again, like.
Krish NAik: It's personal choice, like, working with that, so… like…
Krish NAik: If you're building completely cloud-native solution, like, as the project rise, then only it's beneficial.
Krish NAik: Because from everywhere, you cannot pick up the best. Then they have added is cloud automation, Cloud API models, Cloud Co-work mode, so we really, like, these are the things, not so much related to development, I feel. But a few things with respect to cloud-to-code workflows, I think you will be discussing.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you look into the Enterprise Doc Intelligence System, this is… if anybody has purchased that course.
Krish NAik: Daily amounts.
Krish NAik: That is the upgraded version of the… there is a project, the Doc Intelligence, so now here, few changes have been done from that LLMS.
Krish NAik: Ops, batch? Okay, I'm thinking… so in that way, things have been done.
Krish NAik: So, from the LLM ops, people who have attended, I feel that it's a little bit upgraded version from them.
Krish NAik: Okay, not Agent TKI. This batch is… here you have Langra, but again, Agent TKI, bank will take dedicatedly, like.
Krish NAik: 6 to 7 different types of frameworks. That is dedicated. They are nothing with respect to LLMs, or… because in our case, in our, simply, like, three people, we take it. Like, I focus much more on RAG,
Krish NAik: And advanced SLMs, like, in enterprises, what type of SLMs are used? Like, liquid AI, foundationals, like, what is posting, those type of topics, I think.
Krish NAik: Sunny's work is much more the foundational Gen AI, with that complete end-to-end in AWS.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everything, that part. Mang deals entirely in projects, whether it can be no-code, innate and stuff, and everything. So in that, we're, like, 3 people, 3 different pillars that…
Mitesh Shah: Paul, I have a question.
Mitesh Shah: Are you.
Krish NAik: Yes, it's done, people can drop. Simply, if you don't have questions, you can…
Mitesh Shah: So, Paul, question,
Mitesh Shah: Mine would be taking an Agentic AI course separately?
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: There are already previous two cohorts of Agent TKI 1.0 in there, I took class, Agents really doesn't interest me so much, so I don't like too much of Agents.
Krish NAik: Because in the market, 40-50 libraries are there. Out of that, only the major ones, like Langraph, the Microsoft Agent Tech Library, do things related to NA10. Now, NA10, also, I feel that…
Krish NAik: The market was… Good, high, pipe, slowly, slowly, it's going down.
Mitesh Shah: Make and edit them both are gone, almost gone.
Mitesh Shah: We just launched a new version of it, Agentic 1, but…
Mitesh Shah: things are just pretty good. Anyways, so, .
Krish NAik: Sunny will be there, Anchan.
Mitesh Shah: By when this course would be launched? Any idea?
Krish NAik: Which one?
Mitesh Shah: Agent DeGear.
Krish NAik: AgentK, after this, that will only come.
Mitesh Shah: Not now.
Krish NAik: But before that, in your batch.
Krish NAik: the advanced syllabus that I'll be, I think the… after this, because I think your batch will be till, like, mid of April or the third week of April, as I'm not traveling, so a few more topics that I'll be taking. But, in that only, by first week of April, you will be getting the draft from me, that this is the advanced
Krish NAik: syllabus, and then, like I told, 60%, I will decide. 30-40% you people, can let me know you're in.
Krish NAik: But that will be a little bit of reinforcement learning, how to add it in RAG, how to add it in LLM. My idea is to, this time, get into reinforcement learning. None others are actually dealing with it, and I feel that it's really good for your building a proper feedback system.
Krish NAik: Really, like, human in the loop is not a solution every time. You need to prove that stuff. So, daily, in good organizations, they actually work on that. So, a little bit, my side will be everything, like, from VLLMs, LLMs.
Krish NAik: a RAG, pretty much advanced part with respect to everything, like, whatever the thing that you have learned, their only optimizations will go.
Krish NAik: Whatever the things that you have done, high-level optimizations, scalar, binary, okay, those type of optimizations only, because I know that the fundamental things will…
Krish NAik: You guys already know in front, so I'll be taking that, right?
Amarsrinivas: Is that for next batch call?
Krish NAik: that my next wife, that is only for, I think, in the morning that I was telling, no, for it was around morning 6 that I went planning.
Mitesh Shah: Hey, Paul, we were talking about something, which,
Mitesh Shah: which would not require rack, some… some…
Mitesh Shah: Library that came up with… I don't remember the name, index something. Llama index name.
Krish NAik: page index.
Mitesh Shah: these index.
Krish NAik: The name was.
Mitesh Shah: So, session only record, right?
Krish NAik: Yeah, yeah, that extra session, I've already kept it in mind.
Krish NAik: Why would we be taking one page interlab? That is the vector-less idea.
Krish NAik: It works, but again, there are a few cons in that particular product.
Krish NAik: Okay, because that is also a paid one.
Krish NAik: Definitely.
Mitesh Shah: Got it. Thank you. Thank you, boss.
Krish NAik: Yes, I will let you know, because your badge now, I'll be extending, I will be adding a few more topics related to… little bit of security, I'll be discussing with this badge, don't worry. Like, prompt card.
Krish NAik: guardrails, I'll be discussing. Though it's not part of the syllabus, as I'm not traveling, so I think I can do that.
Krish NAik: So, by end of April, you can take it a rough… Estimated idea.
Krish NAik: Any new batches will come, see, whenever you get fresh post on LinkedIn, get from there. I know that this batch will be starting today, and it's anybody who wants to start their Gen AI journey, it's, like, really good. Everything is there for a foundational perspective, I think.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, really. But,
Krish NAik: Now, from here, you have to understand that once you start exploring much advanced things with respect to LLMs.
Krish NAik: VLLMs, anything.
Krish NAik: The infrastructure requirement will be high.
Krish NAik: This is the first on the muzz. It means that everything Free is not… Like, possible.
Krish NAik: Basic stuff is fine, but actually, in real time, I know that most of the data is unstructured.
Krish NAik: With a hand for… to work with that data, you need good cheap links.
Krish NAik: Dutchland.
Krish NAik: Here's fine-tuning in my… so, in this course, also, if somebody gets it, there is the fine-tuning part, I think DPO, DPO, okay, like, I think only two adapters are discussed, Lora to Lora, I'll be adding much more. I'll be adding DORA, Vora, okay, those advanced adapters also.
Krish NAik: LoRaQLoRa, pretty much old stuff, I feel. 2024. We are in 2026, so…
Krish NAik: better things are there, you have to understand. So, like, I'll be creating that, don't worry. When I have that draft, you will understand. That's why the…
Krish NAik: price also of that course will be high, not that… it's not for beginners, that's why we'll tell that if you want to really do the practical, you have to understand that you need to spend.
Krish NAik: Even I will be spending in my practical. For example, if I want to do a GPT, building, it will take, I know, like, I can do it under, 30 minutes, but I have to launch 8 parallel GPTs.
Krish NAik: Okay, or probably 16 GPUs, or 24 GPUs that I'll be paying in one shot. So I know that for that practical, I will be spending close to $200.
Krish NAik: So those type of advanced R&D stuff, it's not application stuff, I'll be focusing much more on R&D, so that, less… not for 2 to 3 years of experience, anybody more than 5 years of experience, for them, the course will be much more suitable.
Krish NAik: Learning AI is damn cost.
Krish NAik: very costly, like, really.
Krish NAik: just to do experiments, you need to spend a lot of money. That is the problem. It's like a web product, enterprise deployment platform just to do the experiments.
Krish NAik: Now, the main problem is, like, building datasets. So, how to build synthetic data sets?
Krish NAik: Okay, how to create your own evaluation data sets for your LLM, so those type of things. So, little bit, if you guys know about BERT,
Krish NAik: like, the…
Krish NAik: I think everybody knows about transformers, yes, in this class. If you don't know, then we can decide, like, if you want to take that decoder-specific approach, encoder-specific approach, or, like, a sequence-to-SQL approach where we take both
Krish NAik: Of those things, okay, because those are the fundamentals, if those things are not comfortable, then we have to start from that. So, I'll be taking all those inputs from you, and based on that only I'm interested.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, I think, next, anybody can go ahead. I think, Ravi is there, Jagapati is here, Abhijith is there. Okay, I have unmuted you guys.
Abhijit Prusty: April Abhijit here.
Krish NAik: AI widget board.
Abhijit Prusty: Paul, I just wanted to ask, like, we are learning this RAG bootcamp, right?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes.
Abhijit Prusty: of building our fundamentals and the core, whatever we have studied till now, if you practice and do those things, keeping aside all the tools and all, whatever you are saying, like, this currently the Lightning A, is that sufficient, like, just to make the fundamentals and core strong?
Krish NAik: Poor, only with respect to RAD, that part will be done.
Krish NAik: After this course, like, after, till the end of April, I can say that part will be transferred.
Abhijit Prusty: So, for example, like, Paul, I want to, do something real to the applied gen AI in the product, like, use the tools to integrate and all, in terms of the RAG pathway. So, is that okay for us to go through this course, and whatever we have learned, use that, or anything else we should also learn along with this?
Krish NAik: You don't need, but exactly, see, I don't know your requirement. If you can tell me that this is my exact requirement, okay, now, based on that, I can let you know that, okay, you are going in the right track or not. Sometimes, like, you might need some other components.
Krish NAik: I can say that to you.
Abhijit Prusty: I'll draft an email with my… what I'm looking for as a… what is the next I'm looking for. Maybe that you can help me, respond.
Krish NAik: Because, see, really, I always take the decision based on the type of data.
Krish NAik: Okay? Like, till the time I don't know the data, I don't say anything in a client meeting. I just keep… I say always give them.
Abhijit Prusty: For me, Paul, it is more than data, it is about, like, the direction where I should go in.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. You can tell me that this is the type of data, then also that I should have the idea with respect to data, what are the sources, like external sources, internal sources, at least in that. Because RAG, I don't feel everywhere you need to add RAG. Till the time you don't have external sources, you don't need them.
Abhijit Prusty: And the second thing, Paul, like, in terms of our path related to the carrier, right, that also had some questions. Can I drop your email to you with my questions?
Krish NAik: Alright, drop me a move. I think last, because the people dropped, I really didn't respond it. Okay, I will respond coming this week.
Abhijit Prusty: Sure, sure. Thanks, Walk.
Krish NAik: Okay, already touched. Next, Ravi, I think you can go ahead, Ravi.
Ravi: Hi, Paul. Yeah, it's a nice session. So, my question is, I have the experience in AWS engine, so is it possible to add me into the project as a contributor?
Krish NAik: Have you figured the form?
Ravi: Yeah, yeah, I did, yeah.
Krish NAik: I will look into that. See, I've already sent the mail, so again, like, I don't want to do or add any people. Okay, I want to keep that, but let me see. If I see your profile is much more aligned according to the requirements, then I will think about it.
Krish NAik: But I won't commit that I won't… because, see, the leads, and they can let me know that,
Krish NAik: Whether they have a requirement, if they don't have… because I know that if I selected 10 people, 3 people will be unfit. Like, they will say that I'm busy due to office work and some other things. In that case, one or two guys that I can do. But again, it will be the call of the leaders, nothing from myself.
Krish NAik: I've just formed the group, and totally, now the leads will take care of.
Ravi: Okay, okay, yeah, no.
Krish NAik: Because, see, this is the first time I'm doing this particular testing, so, like, I don't want to, do in that way. Let's keep it rigid, let's see whether it works or not. Are we getting something fruitful, something successful after 2 months? That's my… if this model successes, then probably in my next patch, after 1 month or two months only, I will form the tools, okay?
Ravi: Yeah, yeah, sure. So, regarding some… I have questions related to the career progression, so, is it possible for you to look into the if I send email with those questions?
Krish NAik: Okay, drop me a meal for that. App accurate questionnaire? Okay, drop me a meal.
Ravi: Yeah, yeah, sure, Park, yeah, thank you.
Krish NAik: Alright, you are a solution architect, Najo, too.
Krish NAik: Okay, Naga, then, probably let me see in Azure group, I can, item. Okay? Azure part, if you really want, because in AWS, I know, like, they are good, so that part, I will add in.
Ravi: Yeah.
Krish NAik: I'll wait another.
Krish NAik: All right, now. Azure part, I will do that. If you have done that.
Krish NAik: That's the main thing. See, really, when I look into the format, some very high things, like, everybody doesn't mention about that, like, why. Now, that becomes…
Naga: Paul, can you, Henny?
Krish NAik: relative.
Naga: See, like, I have, even done, agentic AI in Azure… Azure AI, like, especially, like, calendar integration. For example, like, meeting invites are there, right?
Naga: example, corporate meeting invites are there, and those… using those invites, using Microsoft Graph API, and
Naga: making the calls to either send them, send the meeting minutes, and then after the meeting, the bot joins the meeting, and then, records the call, or rather, finds the minutes, and then sends it back to all the participants, like, prepares the PDF, and those kind of stuff's also I've done, even in Azure.
Naga: So, I'm pretty good in Azure and AWS, both areas, but, yeah.
Naga: Azure, AWS, I'm currently working on AWS very strongly, but yeah, I can automate in both.
Krish NAik: Okay, then only one, probably in Azure only then, because when I look into the form response, I just wait.
Naga: AWS, Azure Databricks, and, I've worked extensively. In fact, I'm right now, I can contribute.
Krish NAik: Alright, alright, Azure part, then I will do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you're told, okay, team member. Okay, fine, team member is fine.
Naga: Local.
Krish NAik: Alright, I will add you in that meeting.
Naga: Awesome.
Soham Dutta: Hello, Paul.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Soham Dutta: It's a homicide.
Krish NAik: Yeah, I know that phone.
Soham Dutta: Paul, one question. Currently, I'm building an application of BASIS. I have a, like, I've made an ML model of linear HVC.
Soham Dutta: and random forest, using to predict the vehicle category. Basically, if I have the vehicle name, I can categorize the scooter as a bike, right, as one of my org initiatives. Now, the entire dataset is ready right now, right? Now, let's say I wanted to build a rag on top of probably embeddings.
Soham Dutta: Where there's any new vehicle that is coming up, right? I can actually classify that.
Soham Dutta: Lake, can you tell me…
Krish NAik: Rad, why, first of all, just tell me, like, you are working on, like, let's take the example, like, a vehicle classification.
Krish NAik: Something like that?
Soham Dutta: Yes, correct, right.
Krish NAik: So, like, first of all, before RAG, you should work with some type of, like, what type of data you have? Image?
Krish NAik: Video?
Soham Dutta: I have image, I have image, I have text documents, and there are, the tables also. So, already there is a dataset that… so what would happen is, let's say I have already done this and created a master dataset in a tabular format, right, which is in the SQL ingest format. Now, going forward, there will be a lot of vehicles that will be coming from different public sources, different journals. I want to call it all of them.
Soham Dutta: And then want to probably build that as a pipeline. So what do you suggest here, Paul?
Krish NAik: See, for generally, I will suggest…
Krish NAik: before… okay, one part of this is the document passing part. From where you separate out the images, that is the first priority domain.
Soham Dutta: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, once you have, from all the documents, try to build a classification model.
Krish NAik: Vision. Okay, now, from there, you can keep a class, like an unknown class, later on, which you can tag it and update your model. That will be better, at least, I think that.
Soham Dutta: Yes, actually, we have done that, so there is very high, low confidence score that we have, no? We have.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, that you were, the return type of the object detection model which you were using.
Soham Dutta: Correct, correct. So, I was just thinking, let's say, if the… if I have a dataset, which, let's say, every vehicle, will be tagged as a bike scooty, it will have a manufacturer name, and it will have a… so, a vehicle name, let's say, can be, Splendor 125, right? Correct. Now, when the Splendor 125 comes, I will have 4 extractions that I'm doing.
Soham Dutta: First is, let's say, Maker, which is my Honda, then model name is Splendor, and then Bike and Spooty.
Soham Dutta: This is what I'm tagging, 3 extraction variables. Now, let's say any new name that comes on.
Soham Dutta: be it of any name, like, basically NER or, like, any other pattern, I should be able to extract the exactly same 3 columns. So, this is not… this is not a rag problem, right? I'm just asking.
Krish NAik: Yes, see, later on, if I don't know, actually, like, I can take that image, okay, and I can use any type of VLLN to identify that, okay? And later on, our verifications from a truth source, from the original vehicle
Krish NAik: website, like the Honda, or from the… about that particular product, I have to do the verification. In that way, yes, I can build that.
Krish NAik: But, like, the rag, I feel that, a lesser rag.
Krish NAik: Because your main part is document path.
Soham Dutta: Correct, right, right, right. So, I was thinking, let's say if I build an embeddings of the entire dataset, right? I have probably, around two…
Soham Dutta: to, 3,000 unique vehicle class categories, right? For the entire Indian market, as well as South Asian market.
Soham Dutta: And I use… can I build an embedding on top of it, and I just… what currently happening is, right now, either we… I am… I… like, in my organization, there is something… I have a Gemini suit, right? AI studio.
Krish NAik: There is no problem.
Soham Dutta: if I build a prompt out of it, no, the same output is probably giving a different output every time. It's a lot of hallucinations is happening. And since we have already built that model, one of my organization's VP is saying that, can you build… can you use our existing stack of Google Gemini?
Soham Dutta: Rather than building a full-scale model. Now, already I have developed that full-scale model with a very high accuracy.
Soham Dutta: Now, the question is they wanted to… they want… they are pushing me to use a Gemini, because it's… will give me an end. It will not have any separate MLOps layer. Gemini will take care of everything.
Soham Dutta: So I was just thinking whether we should, directly use, or… within Gemini itself, can I use a ML model that can predict this, right?
Krish NAik: ML model, I won't prefer, because this is 2026, that is not the standard. Back in 2017, 18, people used to build a machine learning model with SVM that… but again, what is the purpose of that ML model? Just tell me that. Like, for example, if you're, like,
Krish NAik: you are planning for an SBM classifier, so exactly what is the.
Soham Dutta: Correct. Correct.
Krish NAik: See, SVM classifier was old. Back after 2018, nobody.
Soham Dutta: Okay, great, great.
Krish NAik: That's why. From architectural, I won't go with that. But exactly, like, what is your requirement? Why do you feel that the requirement of machine learning is there?
Soham Dutta: Okay, so I'll… can I just draft you a mail about, what is the requirement, what is the expectations, where that… then you can ask.
Krish NAik: A little bit, yes, you can give me a high level, because first.
Soham Dutta: How did you guys?
Krish NAik: I should go with machine learning, that is my main thing. If I can avoid that,
Krish NAik: I feel that it's better, because based on the data as you have, as you have image and other stuff, machine learning won't be my first priority. So, if it is possible through convolutions, if I can handle it, I can do. If it is required, I can bring in VLLM into the system.
Krish NAik: Okay, for further things, but, little bit, from machine gun, because the standards are moved after 2018, that's it.
Soham Dutta: Okay, I'll probably just draft a very small mail, high level, and then you can pass on your inputs.
Krish NAik: Yes. The main thing is, like, why you thought…
Soham Dutta: What you're trying to say.
Soham Dutta: I got it. I'll still discuss with my co-workers, and I'll get back to you, Paul.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes. Japinder, I don't think you need to join today's class, it's a regular, I will start in the other batch at night. So, really, like, students from this batch, really, night class, you don't need to do. There again, I will teach Lance generally. Okay, so that's why it doesn't make sense.
Rajat Khanna: Hi, Paul. Yes. Can I share my screen?
Krish NAik: Yeah, yeah, you were in panelists, no?
Rajat Khanna: Yeah.
Krish NAik: The analyst, guys, don't ask. Start sharing directly.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, then, let's come to iPhone.
Krish NAik: Who is iPhone, then comes Admin. Admin, Jagaphati also, I…
Krish NAik: So, one by one, you guys can do it. Yes, first of all, you tell me what is the issue?
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so, I tried to install this, Quinn VL.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, leave that part, leave that part, not an issue.
Rajat Khanna: End up.
Krish NAik: You don't need to run this cell, I told in class.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: Cape and hash.
Krish NAik: An execute, okay, now, you really don't need to run that cell, yes.
Rajat Khanna: And this rag is also.
Krish NAik: Yeah, show me the error. What is the error?
Krish NAik: No, no, go below, go below, go below.
Krish NAik: Dodge type… okay, you need to install accelerate, I called? No, install two packages, transformers.
Rajat Khanna: It is there, is he accelerated.
Krish NAik: Install accelerate, then also.
Rajat Khanna: It shows, like, accelerate is installed, so that's…
Krish NAik: Just do a pip install, accident.
Krish NAik: If it is telling its messing, please do that. Chagavati, okay, I will add you to panel.
Krish NAik: Okay, do that in front of me, do a PIP install accelerate.
Krish NAik: Okay, writing, John, today, please give that notebook link. Okay, now that you are asking for the notebook link, just read.
Krish NAik: Ctrl-Shift-V… Really enjoy sitting at the table.
Krish NAik: After I've shared the, team chat, I think I have shared. Yes, the collab link I have shared.
Rajat Khanna: Still, the error is there.
Krish NAik: Go above, go above.
Krish NAik: Yeah, fully where you can go wrong?
Krish NAik: Okay, go up, go up.
Krish NAik: Before this, if there is a… because, restart the kernel once.
Krish NAik: Okay, go below. First of all, do the import section. I think, directly import that cell, no? These things are already there. You don't need to do this.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine. When we were utilized, that is the Python package issue because of that you were getting. Go below.
Krish NAik: Okay, go below.
Krish NAik: Yes, no.
Krish NAik: Okay, now run this one.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Rajat Khanna: And, Paul, regarding that AWS group that is, we have created, so, the, the instructor or the, admins who are there, they will be deciding the project that we will be doing, or is it, some common project that you will share and we all will be working on?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, like, I have already shared a rough architecture, if you remember that AWS infra, on top of that. Now, the leads can decide, like, whether… because the idea is first to work on the main MVP, and later on switch and try to make it out like a private, like a BPC server if, through that, if you want to get…
Krish NAik: Okay, now the leads will decide, and later on, they can let me. You don't really need to worry. Let the leaders decide, first of all, the stack. Once they have finalized it, then they… So, nothing from my side, I am not going to indulge myself.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, thank you, thank you, Alan.
Rajat Khanna: based on check.
Krish NAik: Okay, Jagapati, I think you can share.
Krish NAik: Okay, now from admin… I asked you to unmute, admin iPhone, Admin and iPhone.
Admin: Paul.
Admin: Can I go?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, yes.
Admin: Okay, so basically, I have two questions.
Admin: Basically, I have two questions. First thing is, like, when we are talking about all these infrastructure charges, what do you suggest? Like, do you suggest a machine which can be bought, or a cloud will be more than enough? But again, like, I don't know that, like.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, CCC. Generally, I prefer on-prem when I need high-level security.
Krish NAik: For example, if I'm working with Indian banks.
Krish NAik: they never use cloud, okay? That's why. They have dedicated on-prem things. In that case, probably an H100, like, two H100s, I will do a setup there. But in your case, for learning, you don't need a proper hardware, no?
Krish NAik: you can take it, because if you try to get a GPU right now, in today's market.
Krish NAik: A proper GPU might charge you 3.5 lakhs while you're spending? I feel that if you spend more, like, 5,000 rupees, at least you can learn the basics. And in every organization, they will be providing the cloud. Later on, you can switch, and you can use it for your own R&D stuff. So, don't get the hardware.
Krish NAik: do the hardware if you're purely into R&D stuff, and then only it… but again, I feel that use office
Krish NAik: I can say it's, like, whichever the subscriptions, cloud subscriptions they have.
Krish NAik: You'll get an hardware.
Admin: Yeah, understood, but generally, like, offices nowadays, like, I don't know, like, unless you are working specifically on this.
Admin: It is very tough to get something from the office itself, so most of the time, we have to invest from our side, that's all.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm telling you, if you're investing, pick up something like…
Krish NAik: I feel like, at least for this type of truck, when only? Because I know that you won't be working with VLLMs always.
Admin: Got it, yeah.
Krish NAik: like, in this course, we have came into this phase that, for multimodal, I don't have any options. So that's why I'm telling you that. Similarly, in your phase, in your…
Krish NAik: when you need that work to R&D to do that, it can be nothing related to your work, but sometimes the RM generally tells, okay, you can use it. If not giving them spend, like, $15, $20 subscriptions are there, I feel that which is more than good. And generally, I suggest most of my students to go with Lightning.
Krish NAik: It's better, okay, for your initial development to do testing, Okay, it's really good.
Krish NAik: My experience for the past 2 years with Lightning has been awesome. I can say that as a developer, it's really good.
Krish NAik: And if you… like, I know very good people working on the product. Sebastian Rashka is working, the CFO, like, I know a few of the people directly from their team, and any problem, if I face, then I can… they have a, I think, Discord group also, where if anything happens with respect to that.
Krish NAik: But you can let them move. So in that way, Developer to dev connectors better.
Admin: Oh, okay, okay.
Admin: Okay, the second thing is, like, are you also, like, the new batch, which currently launched you sometimes back, you showed, are you also taking, some, some, apart?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no. That slot I don't have. Because night 8, 98 already I have a current batch, I think it will go till 1 month, but that batch I won't be going. I will be taking things next slip, because that patch that I am planning, it will be pretty much advanced stuff only, not beginner-level stuff.
Admin: So you will continue that advance batch, and later you will also inform us, right, when the batch.
Krish NAik: In the month of April only, before your batch completes, 2-3 weeks back.
Krish NAik: Okay. I will let you know, okay, and any coupons and anything shared to… for your batch, I will do that from my side.
Rajat Khanna: Paul, I have one add-on question to this.
Admin: I have a last question. Rajit…
Krish NAik: Okay, just wait, huh?
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Admin: Yeah. So, when you talked about this N10, we recently were trying to suggest, people to start with N10, but what I understood, like, I also, read it, like, N10 is not going that great, so what is the alternative, of NA10, which is there in the market, at least, will be there for 2, 3, 4 years, at least?
Krish NAik: See, for no-port solutions, Yes.
Krish NAik: People are actually new to build an MVP irate in your skin.
Krish NAik: But actually, to productionize that stuff, in A10 doesn't give you a lot of control.
Krish NAik: For that, you will be coming back to the main roads only.
Krish NAik: If you… see, if in a product, if you have a service, I can say that, okay, let's hold the service can anytime, really, but it can be a part of the product.
Krish NAik: I cannot say that your entire product is only running on N10. Then you have a very bad dependency. If something happened to N8, okay, if it gets shut down, if it gets deprecated, what happens to the product?
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why. Then you come back to your original roots, like, okay, your SDLC stuff. So, I cannot say right now what is the best alternate. Till now, I feel that.
Krish NAik: Maintenance there, but, no core tools.
Krish NAik: Somehow, I feel that little bit less popularity, like, open claw, again, but again, that is for personal, I cannot suggest for enterprise. But it's really great for personal stuff. Security issues are being solved, I think, in the next few months, but in 18, you can start. I can see that in 18, at least it's there for next 2-3 years. It's not going anywhere.
Krish NAik: They will make their product much better, for sure, they are working on it.
Admin: Okay, okay, yeah, that's for you.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so in that explanation that you are doing, so the advanced course that you are talking about, so in that, do we need to know previously for, data science and machine learning as well?
Krish NAik: Yes.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: need to know transformers, because, see, there I won't be teaching you what is precision, what is recall, what is blue, what is rock scores, those things I won't be teaching.
Krish NAik: fundamental stuff, I won't be dealing. I will be working much more on, like, few, things with respect to, like, few rack components will be there, that you can easily get it. But when I start working with LLMs, now, if I say max sequence length, okay, and you guys, most of them
Krish NAik: know about context, but exactly both are pretty much the same stuff, okay? Now, that's right. Now, you need to have the basic fundamentals of Transformers, because to teach Transformers and to go in-depth, it takes one month.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I won't… my idea is that you guys know transformers. Now, in transformers, there's something, specific to encoder-based approach or decoder-based approach, how to do the fine-tuning of that few things. Because, see, really,
Krish NAik: I can discuss that, but again, that will be… I don't want to spend time on that. Rather than I want to directly start working with LEDs.
Rajat Khanna: So, before starting that class, can you share us the topics that we need to know?
Krish NAik: Don't worry, before that, that will be premium badge, so, like, for those students, I'll be sharing Udemy coupons and other things.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because that… you can simply take that to execute all the practicals in that patch, you have to spend more than, I can say, how much.
Krish NAik: Roughly, 200 tons.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: It can be more also, I don't know, I have to do the exact calculation for all the practicals. Okay, but, that is a rough estimation. At least, I know, $200 will be requested just to do your practicals. Otherwise, you are… you will be just sitting silent in the class.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, and it will be starting in month of, May?
Krish NAik: Me.
Krish NAik: Not May, not May. After your rag batch, you will be getting 2 months of cool-down period.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, then I will start, like, I think your agent's batch will come after your agent's batch. Let me see, like, if I can start it. But again, like, July… July 1st week, that is my target.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, because as I shared with you, no, I'll be, changing the organization, joining the new one, and we'll be…
Krish NAik: Beautiful.
Rajat Khanna: in all those things, so I'll… I'll be more interested to as… as… to have as much as knowledge, with me, so that I can work and all those things.
Krish NAik: That is beneficial, because the purpose of that batch is a little bit different. My idea is people who are having that 20, 30 lakh package, the idea is to move them more, that 56.
Krish NAik: That's why it's from R&D stuff, much more. So anyone more than 3 years of experience, for them only, I can suggest it. In the space of AI, that 3 years should be the best.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: Little Arctic.
Rajat Khanna: Thank you, thank you.
Krish NAik: Jatinar is asking that, okay, so, like, people, when you filled up the form, just wait. If I show you my desktop… Okay, so just wait, there.
Krish NAik: This is this one. Okay, so here, I think, with respect to portions… Okay, now what we'll be building? So here, I get that, gist, okay, so a similar architecture that Azure guys will also be working on.
Krish NAik: This architecture, I shared it multiple times, I think with Rawbo, with Aza. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: That is the starting point here.
Krish NAik: Purely cloud-native stuff, Jatilda.
Krish NAik: Okay, admin done, iPhone, iPhone, you were left.
Krish NAik: You have raised your hand iPhone.
Krish NAik: Bob.
Jagapathi: Polish legroom?
Krish NAik: Yeah, yeah, Jagavati, please start sharing. If you're in terminal, don't, if you're in panelists, don't think. Directly start sharing.
Jagapathi: Yeah, I'm surprised, like, do we need to, like, create a uni file here?
Krish NAik: Show me? Yes.
Krish NAik: What device? I'm an engineer.
Jagapathi: spinner.
Krish NAik: Now, now see, when you see this error, click…
Krish NAik: What is the first thing that you have in your mind?
Krish NAik: Because see, these type of errors, do you think that you should ask me?
Jagapathi: No, actually, I was, getting some other… you just mentioned… Show me that, show me that.
Krish NAik: See, Nick.
Jagapathi: Yes, ma'am.
Krish NAik: By this time, I want you guys to spend time on DNS. It's something like, the more you spend time… no, this cell, actually, you don't need to run it only, I told. This cell, just keep it coming.
Jagapathi: Okay, sure. Yeah, I mean, this no… just now I got this error. I'm trying to execute all this else. I'll look into it.
Krish NAik: Simply just change the input path, the slash content, it is for Google Collab. Okay.
Krish NAik: You can copy that from, click on attention is all you need, left-click, copy the relative path, and paste it there. Don't use slash docs. Okay, yeah.
Krish NAik: do that. The rest, everything is fine.
Krish NAik: And also install Poplar if you have missed that Popular path.
Jagapathi: Yeah, I did install just another one.
Krish NAik: Okay? If you have installed, no, you have… that is an error.
Krish NAik: Okay, they use, pseudo, the keyword.
Jagapathi: Pseudo-pip, or just…
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no, no, not here. That,
Krish NAik: It's not pip install popular utils, it will be…
Krish NAik: Sudo, first of all, the access has to be on system level. Just check that command. Go above, go above, go above, it's not pip. You need to install yes this command. You can see aptit install hyphen y popularage. Here, add the command sudo. Yes.
Krish NAik: After exclamation mark, add… don't remove the exclamation mark. It has to be at the first. This is a command.
Jagapathi: Is it cute?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no. Pseudo has to be in the first.
Krish NAik: After exclamation mark. Yes, you do a space, yes. Okay, now run it.
Jagapathi: Okay, sure, Paul. Just one more thing, Paul, like, I'm from different, backgrounds, I'm more into Salesforce.
Jagapathi: I just now attended this course rag.
Krish NAik: It's not settle now.
Jagapathi: I don't know, I'm… I'm here from… since inception.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, okay.
Jagapathi: Yeah, so all I know about A is, like, what is just this RAG course alone, and with little Python experience previously, what I had, I could understand the code.
Jagapathi: I'll be, like, explore the things, what you shared, the…
Jagapathi: you shared some Udemy links, right? So I'll be going through those courses.
Krish NAik: Moon.
Jagapathi: Thank you so fast.
Krish NAik: I didn't share any Udemy. I think in class previously, a few things were there. But, see, in Udemy also, you can get it, rather than…
Krish NAik: Because you know the fundamentals of RAC, probably you need to deep dive into the LLM stuff and a little bit of the agents to get into that Gen AI space that we see in 2026. Three main pillars are there always. That LLMs, VLLMs is one pillar, the other pillar is the RAC pillar, and the third one is basically your agents.
Krish NAik: So, out of this, if you are good in these three pillars, later on you can think about switching or anything like that, if you want.
Krish NAik: Okay, so RAG part, I can say that, okay, fine, and by the end of this course, it will be good in that, but the question comes, the next step. Okay, so you can, look into agents part. I feel that it's easier to explore as compared to LLMs.
Krish NAik: There are lesser concepts, much more application stuff with respect to code, I can say.
Krish NAik: But, for LLMs, you need to spend some time, because you need to learn what is transformers, then from there, encoders, decoders, sequence-to-sequence models, those things comes into the picture.
Krish NAik: So it takes time.
Jagapathi: So, for LLM, do you have any courses from your academy, in Udemy or something?
Krish NAik: I think the recent, badge that got… that is, that will give you an overall holistic idea with Gen AIs.
Krish NAik: From this, you will get a little bit of Langrav, but it's not like that Langrav is very high priority. It's something like my priority is to work much more making Asian integrated. So, but if you're not working with Asian Tegrac, then you can actually look into the course, which is starting today. It will give you… it's something like, I can say.
Krish NAik: I'll always take overview of the entire journey.
Jagapathi: Okay, so that will teach about LLM as well, Mint.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think there is a Transformers module, no. I don't remember, but just wait, let me confirm, because I don't… I haven't gone through step-by-step.
Krish NAik: But, where is the PDF preview preview?
Krish NAik: I'm just sleep.
Krish NAik: Okay, why transformers are the backbone? Transformers, tokenization, yes. What context implementation?
Krish NAik: Because here, the X,
Krish NAik: It has the fundamentals of transformers, I can say. That's why this particular module is their Foundations of modern engineering.
Krish NAik: Transformers Architecture, you can see no core concept.
Jagapathi: Okay, sure, Paul. Last week, you mentioned do you plan to take some,
Jagapathi: class in the middle of the week, right? This week?
Krish NAik: Yes, I'm planning, but, till now, like, leave me this week after that, because I was planning, because, like, I was… my travel plans were there, but now it is canceled. Okay, so because of that, I can extend the batch, okay, and few additional more topics that I'll be discussing. I will create the plan, and next week, as we start our multimodal stuff.
Krish NAik: So, yeah, because today we have done, and I think next week, a little bit about the code discussion, architectures discussion. So, just take it. So, it will be extra classes, then I don't need. If I need, I will tell you in the month of April, not in this month.
Krish NAik: Then in the last month only, a few things like, the agent decks, security stuff, and for that, I will take them.
Krish NAik: Those are small, small topics, 60 minutes, 90 minutes time.
Jagapathi: Okay, triple, thank you.
iPhone: So, Paul, the quick question here is, like.
iPhone: Do you have any course on Anthropic Cloud for enterprise type of things?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no. Not. That is, I think, one in the team is working on that.
Krish NAik: But I think the course will come, because that is a small course, 8 to 10 hours of recording only in Anthropic Cloud, if you are asking.
Krish NAik: Only in anthropic claud.
iPhone: I mean, there's a cloud, cloud… like, the… See?
Krish NAik: For Anthropic, see, for Anthropic, in their website, they have dedicatedly 6 to 8 posters, and they are really good.
Krish NAik: If you have time, go through that, rather than, like, depending on someone. Because it's pretty much the same stuff that they have created, then the other guy will again see that stuff. So, directly look into the content of the creator that I will suggest.
Krish NAik: I… it's easy, it's not, like, very hard to understand. There, they don't talk about such architecture-level stuff.
Krish NAik: Okay, they make things easy, so if you have that, look into that, Claude, Anthropic diet.
Krish NAik: Because in this course, also, they have a certain module, but only for that one module. I don't feel that you should get completely one course. Okay, or probably, like, I have not checked other courses, but you can look into it. I know that in the Anthropic Academy, they really have that.
Krish NAik: Very good courses. And all are, like, small, small, 30 minutes, 30 minutes. So if you have that, if you spend 3-4 hours, you will have a very good idea.
iPhone: Okay, and the same thing about the ChatGPT Enterprise.
Krish NAik: I don't, think about ChatGPT, they have that.
iPhone: I mean, like, you know, many big organizations, big organizations, they're getting focused on the…
iPhone: open source and the cloud, and then chat GPT. They don't want to go to cloud vendors and pay lots.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: But, like…
Krish NAik: Only you can get the APIs only, no? Other than that, your main application or your product info will be in some type of cloud or on-prem solution.
iPhone: So, the Olama is, like, also, I've seen a couple of places, they're using the Olama, and they clot together.
Krish NAik: Yes, Ulama has its own cloud where you can take a $20 subscription and you can run anyone.
Krish NAik: Okay.
iPhone: You can have the local as well, right?
Krish NAik: Yes, local as well also you can do it, but again, these are only LLM providers, but your actual product, it cannot be directly there, no.
Krish NAik: It means that any service or that, it has to be setting on top of any cloud or on-prem server. That's my main thing. From there, fine, you are getting the APIs. That is one part.
Krish NAik: But I cannot say that the entire product or the application that you are working, it's… it's entirely on API. It is not possible.
Krish NAik: Okay, it has to be part of that. Few services, probably your LLM service, embedding service, these things, like, if you want to do any type of fine-tuning service, these things, like, they're probably…
Krish NAik: Other than that, your main product, it will be sitting on top of some backend server.
iPhone: Okay, yeah, that's…
Krish NAik: Alright, so I will stop sharing.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, Jak. Tinder, okay, the Anthropic, link, yes, that is a skill jar.
Krish NAik: Yes, correct.
Krish NAik: Is learning MCP a good option? Yes, in some cases, I feel MCP makes your life easier. Okay, so it's not about learning MCP rather than using MCP. MCP is not such a… if you spend, 30 to 60 minutes, you will get the idea. Then the question comes, securing the MCP. That is a tougher talk.
Krish NAik: Okay, because you have to then host your MCP in a custom server, you have to give it a particular domain, accessible to everyone. In that way, that thing happens. But MCP makes your life easier.
Krish NAik: But, everyone is not using MCP, that's it.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, I will work on that, because even I didn't ask for that, this one… let me do it, for that cost us anything.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so let's meet next week. So next week, actually, we will start. Today, you have just given, so, like, collab or Lightning.
Krish NAik: just be sure you take this particular decision by, like, after next Sunday, or, like, you have this week and next week to decide. Next week, practicals.
Krish NAik: I will try to do it in collab, I think one or two will be done, but the third one is not possible. For that, I'll be switching to Lightning Air. So, you have the free credits, so by this time, sir, I know that you have multiple email IDs.
Krish NAik: But, like, test it out. You should have that, at least that 15 credit from Lightning. It will be actually helpful, rather than directly doing the payment.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just be sure you are having that 15 credit, then I know that at least 2 years secured for the next 2 weeks of multimodist.
Krish NAik: Okay, and therefore, final project, if it is required, then I will take.
Krish NAik: No, no, I have not created the complete syllabus. The syllabus will be… it's, in progress work.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think in the month of April, because right now, as I'm extending 2 weeks, so, Pratmesh, like, by the end of April.
Krish NAik: this patch will control. So, we have time to discuss other things also. So, and I think by the first week of April, I will release a draft syllabus of the advanced one to
Krish NAik: Everyone, at least a draft, I believe.
Krish NAik: Pratamish is asking, you can raise your hand, Pratamish.
Krish NAik: Prathamesh, yes. Yes, Prathamish.
Prathmesh Atre: Alright, sir, thanks for unmuting. So, will there be any significant difference, like, what new batch you have currently launched? Like, I think it is starting from today, and, you know, what you are creating in the next month? Like, what are your thoughts?
Krish NAik: Today, the badge that is going, it gives you a journey to start your AI. That is, it gives you an overall idea, exactly.
Krish NAik: Now, see, each thing has its own depth. For example, RAG, if I'm trying to discuss, now nobody can spend so much time on RAG, RAG, RAG, you have to understand. Now, that's why for RAG, a specific batch. Similarly, for agents, a specific batch. And now, this gap gives you… if you're not familiar with GenAI, you can directly start your journey from
Krish NAik: That's why this is a modern route. It means that directly come here.
Krish NAik: The instructor will start with transformers, the fundamentals, and then he will give you an idea with respect to LLMs also, how to do the fine-tuning stuff, then you will discuss agents also, then he will discuss RAM. Each thing has its own depth, you have to understand.
Prathmesh Atre: Right.
Krish NAik: So that's why. So if you are completely new to Gen AI, okay, then this gives you a very good idea about, okay, now, from here, I need to go into much more advanced stuff. So this gives you a complete foundation.
Prathmesh Atre: Right, sir, and the thing which you are going to, you know, proceed with, so, in what particular topic it is going in-depth?
Krish NAik: It will be, in what topic? There won't be any agents?
Prathmesh Atre: It was… haha.
Krish NAik: See, there will be… majorly, the components will be LLMs. Not LLMs, actually, it will be SLMs, okay?
Krish NAik: like, how to fine-tune SLMs, those things will be there. Then comes to your VLLMs part, this multimodal rack, the same thing, but with a little bit different variant that I'll be using there for multimodal stuff. Then comes your reinforcement learning.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, how to, introduce feedback systems to your RAG, LLMs, that part will come into the picture. Okay, and,
Krish NAik: a few things with respect to architectural. So, like.
Krish NAik: How to train deep sick, how to train, like, if I say GPTs, those type of stuff.
Krish NAik: Much more architectural things focus.
Prathmesh Atre: Okay, okay.
Prathmesh Atre: Okay.
Krish NAik: Then, a few things, like, I don't know how many of you follow Andrej Kaparti heavily.
Krish NAik: So something from, he's the repo, he's work that I'll be picking up. It means that the work that I'll be sharing, I will tell you that
Krish NAik: These are the actual sources. It means the sources will be people from OpenAI, people from Tesla, and they are actually doing very good work in the form of actual research, and later on this. Okay, so that's why I'll bring those type of stuff. So that will be pretty much advanced stuff. If you don't know the basics, it becomes a problem. It means that
Krish NAik: then you will say that, okay, I don't know this, you are only… that's right, fundamentals is important. If you know… tell transformers, it's really great. At least the paper attention is all you need. That is the bare minimum requirement to start the course.
Prathmesh Atre: So, like, if we already enrolled in Vigentech V1, like, this, batch, and AI481, I don't think so. The batch which is starting from today, I'll be… have to enroll in it. Like, much difference, like.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think then, just see. I always say, when you are looking into it, just check how many modules you don't.
Krish NAik: Okay, that known to unknown ratio, if you feel that it's more than 30 to 40%, okay, alright, I can say that my… if I'm spending some money, I'll be getting some value out of it. If it's less than that, okay, then really I know that.
Krish NAik: that particular idea that comes out, that I can ex…
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I'm telling you, you have to take that decision. I cannot say that, directly don't purchase it, okay? You have to take that decision, look into the modules, evaluate yourself. Yes, I don't know how many modules. Based on that known-to-unknown ratio, always try to purchase.
Krish NAik: Because when you're spending, because at least for live classes, that, I know people come in, like.
Krish NAik: In recorded mode, that is the toughest. I know that we have courses in Udemy. Okay, the completion rate is 0.36 in the whole world, just think.
Krish NAik: People have purchased, 1 lakh people have purchased the sports.
Prathmesh Atre: It ain't.
Krish NAik: Okay, that is the completion rate, 0.3. So that's why I'm telling you, like, people doesn't complete, it's not… that's why at least we know that in live classes, people will come, it's better to interact.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Prathmesh Atre: But that, that new one that you are going to say related to SLM, that will be, I think, completely new, which,
Krish NAik: Ew.
Prathmesh Atre: We are not covered in the.
Krish NAik: That will be… see, that will be new, that will be costly, because the practical is very costly in that.
Prathmesh Atre: Okay, okay.
Krish NAik: It can mean that, just think about it's not… the thing that we'll be doing for that, the infrastructure is very costly.
Krish NAik: So, generally, like, that's why, like, I will be setting the expectations from day one, like, what are the things, because infrastructure will play a very crucial role.
Krish NAik: Otherwise…
Prathmesh Atre: Like, is there a fine-tuning data stuff is also there.
Krish NAik: highly, everything, SLM fine-tuning. LLM fine-tuning, I cannot teach you. So, I will be dealing with SLMs. So, for RAG-specific, how to build RAG-specific SLM, like, remove OpenA, I don't need, actually, OpenA.
Krish NAik: Because I know most of the systems, they don't expose stuff directly to OpenAI. They will tell that, okay, I have my own data, train data directly.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that, after your retrieval directly, it will go to that, customized LLM, customized SLM that I have built.
Krish NAik: So those type of things, like, really, like, if you want to take a source, last time I also shared something like this, like, I will be using Liquid AI, which is much more enterprise level, okay?
Krish NAik: These are a few of the things, because I will be picking up 2026 standards. It's not anything from AWS-specific and few things. So, this is pretty much research-specific things. So, from here, how to make architecture. So, at least we will try to hit that 8 billion
Krish NAik: Remember that. I'm planning to reach that. That will be the last final project that will be working with something subliminal parameter model, or 8 million planning. But I have to just check out the cost, how much is it costing? That's fine.
Prathmesh Atre: Okay, sir. Sure.
Prathmesh Atre: Okay.
Prathmesh Atre: It will be really fascinating if you, you know, tell any one project. It will be really good to hear.
Krish NAik: Yes, now, how to deploy SLMs in mobile devices. Now, really, that is in my plan, but again.
Krish NAik: That is another developer-specific thing. But again, because for that little bit of core ML is required from,
Krish NAik: iOS devices, similarly in Kotly. So, that's why. I will evaluate, and then once I have the draft syllables, I'll be sharing with you guys. Okay, then from there, I'll be taking the inputs, like, what are the things, and estimated cost, also, I need to prepare for that. That will be a 5 months batch, 5 to 6 months, so I know that every month, if you are paying…
Krish NAik: It's not, because I know that you will be paying more to Insta, and less to me. Just remember that billing concept.
Prathmesh Atre: Okay, bro.
Prathmesh Atre: That would keep it affordable, not very much high.
Krish NAik: That will be high, because my target audience will be at least people who are in that field. Because I told you, mine is, like, people who are having that
Krish NAik: 25 to 30 LPA to move them to 50 to 60 LPA.
Krish NAik: Okay, that will be my target, so that's fine. It's not like that, because I know that then there is no benefit of purchasing the course. If you think that I cannot spend on Impera just to see the stuff, okay, because the things that I'll be doing, I know that after 8 months, they will be deprecated.
Krish NAik: You have to understand that.
Krish NAik: Because, again, some new model will come, until the time we'll be completing the patch. That is the problem. But once you know the process, you can get and add that stuff.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why it won't be affordable like any other batches.
Prathmesh Atre: Alright, sir.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Prathmesh Atre: Ryan, thank you.
Krish NAik: I mean… Mantage, yes, Mantage, you have raised.
Mantaaj: Hey, hi. Hi, Paul. Thanks for the session, Paul. Paul, I'm, I just had… I was listening to the conversation that, was being done between all the other members and between you. I'm just a little confused now that for this upcoming course, right, as
Mantaaj: as because I'm not from AIML background.
Mantaaj: I'm, from other background, from…
Mantaaj: So, I have done this rack course from you. Now, as we are moving to the advanced course, right, which will be more of.
Krish NAik: For you, see, generally, like, I will suggest a course if you are having 3 years of working experience in the AI domain, and then only otherwise only.
Mantaaj: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's… see, if you're actually not working, it doesn't make sense to explore those advanced topics. It's only for them who are working.
Krish NAik: I hope you get my point. Then why I will suggest anyone? Because I know that at least 3 to 4 years, you should be working with such things. Then it becomes. Otherwise, simply, like, you can start with the JM AI, which is starting today. It will give you much better foundation. And I think you are in the night batch also, no?
Mantaaj: Yes.
Krish NAik: see, RAG part I will discuss there also, but not so much from LLMs and other fine-tuning part, but you have to understand it there also I taught how to fine-tune distilled GPT.
Krish NAik: Okay, and, distal part. Okay, now those are actually one type of SLMs.
Krish NAik: having lower, as I told in the class. So, like, I've told you the fine-tuning, but here, probably, a few other things, like adapters with respect to LoRa.
Krish NAik: Q, Laura, those things will be, taught here. Few things with respect to quantize. Okay, yes, I think another important topic, which is not really here, quantization later on that in the advanced course that I will be including, quantization plays a very crucial role.
Krish NAik: So, few things like there, like, again, we have to decide. So, I feel that don't go with the advanced one, rather than take something from here, because in user batch, you already have the fundamentals covered with you, and this AI will be a much better space tag. And later on, you can actually, if you want.
Krish NAik: Okay, once we have successfully completed that advancement, you can look into the recording, because that is very, very niche content. Nobody is teaching, that's all.
Mantaaj: Okay, okay. Thanks, thanks, Paul, for this addition, yeah.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay.
Krish NAik: All right, guys, so I think then I'll be concluding the session for today. So next week, just be sure you have Lightning AI account with you. Collab is fine, the free tariff collab. These two things are next week. Next to next week, Lightning AI completely, that I'll be building. Okay? So, just be sure you keep those things in your mind.
Krish NAik: And, already one sample tutorial we have discussed. Next, I think, will be working with dock lengths and other things that, names from NVIDIA that also we'll be exploring for multimodal, right? So pretty much, a lot of things. So for… we'll be exploring, at least, I can say.
Krish NAik: 3 weeks.
Krish NAik: So I know that till first of, first week of April, you will be doing a deep dive. I will be discussing a lot of things which are not mentioned in your syllabus from multimodal style, okay? But I feel that it is important in 2026 much more, because most of the production systems, they have multimodal.
Krish NAik: Okay, and nobody was building completely text. Yes, fewer building, but I feel the amount of data around us is much more unstructured. If you can handle multimodal, it's very easy to handle textual data.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: All right, so, by the way, everyone, thanks for joining. Let's,
Krish NAik: Explore, from next week, the multimodal track systems.